<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Home on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/</link><description>Recent content in Home on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Happy Pride Month!</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2021-2022/2021-06-14-happy-pride-month/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2021-2022/2021-06-14-happy-pride-month/</guid><description>From all of us at the CCSS, happy pride month!
Here is a list of amazing resources for LGBTQIA2S+:
Carleton&amp;rsquo;s Women in Computer Science Pride Series on Instagram Gender &amp;amp; Sexuality Resource Centre LGBT YouthLine The Trevor Project</description></item><item><title>Winter 2021 Feedback and Suggestions Survey Results</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2021-2022/2021-06-04-winter-feedback-survey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2021-2022/2021-06-04-winter-feedback-survey/</guid><description>As elected student representatives of the Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS), it is important that undergraduate computer science students under the School of Computer Science (SCS), studying at Carleton University, have their voices heard through channels that they can trust.
Due to COVID-19, many students have expressed concerns regarding challenges in an online learning environment. Similar to the Fall 2020 SCS Undergraduate Feedback &amp;amp; Suggestions Survey that was created for computer science students to share their experiences and opinions regarding online courses with the School of Computer Science (SCS) administration, staff, and faculty members (that report can be found here and the password was sent to all B.</description></item><item><title>Speed Friending</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-04-09-speed-friending/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-04-09-speed-friending/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blockchain + Crypto Q&amp;A Session</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-04-07-blockchain-crypto-qa-session/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-04-07-blockchain-crypto-qa-session/</guid><description>Description We have invited Jeremy Clark, an associate professor at the Concordia Institute for Information Systems Engineering, back for an interactive Q&amp;amp;A session to continue the discussion on crypto and blockchain technology!
Given that there were many audience questions left unanswered during his previous lecture, and many of you expressed interest in having Jeremy back, we are very happy to be hosting this follow-up discussion session.</description></item><item><title>CCSS X SCS Feedback and Suggestions Survey</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-04-04-winter-feedback-survey/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-04-04-winter-feedback-survey/</guid><description>As we’re nearing the end of the Winter term, how was this term compared to the Fall term? Was it better, worse, or the same? What did you find challenging?
The Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS) wants to hear from you! It is important to us that students have their voices heard through channels that they can trust and are comfortable with. As the elected student representatives this school year, we have many opportunities to share student experiences and opinions with the School of Computer Science (SCS) and its faculty members, including teaching staff.</description></item><item><title>Board of Directors Election Results 2021-2022</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-03-30-election-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-03-30-election-results/</guid><description>Congratulations to our upcoming Board of Director members, and thank you to all candidates for getting involved with the CCSS! A complete breakdown of the election results can be seen in the PDF here!
The 2021-2022 CCSS board will be as follows:
President:
Sarah Ali Vice President:
Erica Li Director of Finance:
Victor Li Director of Academics:
Matthew MacRae-Bovell Director of Social:</description></item><item><title>Winter Prof Social</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-26-prof-social/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-26-prof-social/</guid><description>Description In the spirit of staying connected with one another in a remote learning environment, the CCSS cordially invites you to a virtual Prof Social, to be hosted on Zoom!
During the event, students and faculty members will have a chance to mingle with one another in a number of breakout rooms. At regular intervals, participants will be prompted to switch rooms and continue the conversation with new faces! This event was inspired by the Prof Nights from previous years, and serves as a COVID-safe substitute.</description></item><item><title>Become a Senior Engineer in 2 years</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-24-become-a-senior-developer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-24-become-a-senior-developer/</guid><description>Description Ryan Latta will be talking about what it takes to become a Senior level engineer! This talk will discuss what qualities make a great Senior Developer, and what you can start learning and practicing today that will help you become a Senior Engineer within 2 years of starting your career!
Ryan Latta has been in the software industry for over a decade. He has worked launching his own start-ups and in Fortune 100 companies doing everything from software development to acting as a CTO.</description></item><item><title>Science Society Super Social</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-03-20-society-super-social/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-03-20-society-super-social/</guid><description>Description Looking to meet and mingle with other students from Computer Science and Engineering? The CCSS, WiCS, SCESoc, and WISE are organizing a fun get-together on gather.town on Saturday, March 20 from 5-7 pm EDT!
During the first hour, we will have an ice breaker game, geoguessr, and skribbl, with prizes up for grabs! During the second hour, there will be time to chat with each other and optionally play some mini games!</description></item><item><title>Election Candidate Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-03-14-election-platforms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-03-14-election-platforms/</guid><description>Election Candidate Platforms The CCSS Elections for 2021-2022 have begun! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce that we have 15 candidates running for positions on the board of directors.
$(document).ready(function(){ shuffle(); function shuffle(){ $(".president").each(function(){ var divs = $(this).find('div'); for(var i = 0; i The Candidates are: President: Sarah Ali William So Vice President: Ayodeji Akinbile Erica Li Malcolm Smith Director of Finance: Benjamin Karstad Victor Li Director of Academics: Aaditya (Adi) Chopra Matthew MacRae-Bovell Robert Babaev Director of Social: Jerry Liu Milo Goodfellow Veronica Yung Director of Community: Patrick Ene Zara Ali Sarah Ali - President I’m currently serving as a Communications Officer on the Board of Directors and I’m excited to have a chance to lead the new board into the future of the CCSS for the next academic year!</description></item><item><title>Speed Friending</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-03-12-speed-friending/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-03-12-speed-friending/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Blockchain and Cryptocurrency Landscape</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-10-blockchain-crypto-landscapes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-10-blockchain-crypto-landscapes/</guid><description>Recording Click here to view the recording.
Description The School of Computer Science has invited Jeremy Clark, an associate professor at the Concordia Institute for Information Systems Engineering, to give a lecture on cryptocurrencies and blockchain technology!
The lecture will explore the world of decentralized finance and showcase the groundbreaking research taking place in this area! :scientist:
For more information, please visit: https://carleton.ca/scs/cu-events/ccss-presents-the-blockchain-and-cryptocurrency-landscape/</description></item><item><title>Project Showcase</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-05-project-showcase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-05-project-showcase/</guid><description>Description SCESoc and the CCSS are collaborating this semester to bring you an epic Project Showcase Night!
Got any side projects or class projects you&amp;rsquo;re super stoked about sharing? Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve been developing a game or a website that you really want to show off.
Join us all on March 5th to present your projects (finished or not!) to your peers! Sign up here if you want to showcase your project: https://forms.</description></item><item><title>A Chat With Ross Video</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-02-a-chat-with-ross-video/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-02-a-chat-with-ross-video/</guid><description>Description Shawn Snider, current VP Production Workflow and Cloud Services at Ross Video and Carleton University graduate, will be sharing his experience in the workforce. He will discuss why he made the decision to join Ross, his career progression, and how his education and continuous learning has helped him along the way! As always, there will be a Q&amp;amp;A to follow to answer all your questions!</description></item><item><title>CCSS Elections 2021</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-02-26-elections/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-02-26-elections/</guid><description>There are six positions to run for:
President Vice President Director of Finance Director of Academics Director of Social Director of Community You can find the full election timeline and further details on the electoral policies outlined in our Writ of Election.
Interested in running for a position? Fill out the nomination form by Wednesday, March 3.
Please contact elections@ccss.carleton.ca with any questions or concerns regarding the CCSS elections.</description></item><item><title>Winter General Meeting</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/society/2021-02-26-winter-general-meeting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/society/2021-02-26-winter-general-meeting/</guid><description>Description The CCSS Winter General Meeting will be taking place this Friday, February 26 at 6:00 PM EST.
At the meeting, we will discuss the goals of the society, report on this year&amp;rsquo;s accomplishments, kick off the CCSS 2021 General Election period, and allow members to ask society-related questions directly to the Board of Directors. All CCSS members (that&amp;rsquo;s you!) are encouraged to attend the general meeting to be well-informed about the activities of the society.</description></item><item><title>Afternoon Among Us</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-25-amoung-us/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-25-amoung-us/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Speed Friending</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-25-speed-friending/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-25-speed-friending/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Connect 4 Tournament</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-24-connect4-tournament/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-24-connect4-tournament/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Fall Feedback and Suggestions Survey Report</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-02-24-fall-feedback-survey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-02-24-fall-feedback-survey/</guid><description>As elected student representatives of the Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS), it is important that undergraduate computer science students under the School of Computer Science (SCS), studying at Carleton University, have their voices heard through channels that they can trust.
Due to COVID-19 in 2020, many students have expressed concerns regarding challenges in an online learning environment. Therefore, Tiffany Lau (the 2020-2021 Director of Community) and William So (the 2020-2021 President) have created an SCS Undergraduate Feedback &amp;amp; Suggestions Survey for computer science students to share their experiences and opinions regarding online courses this term with the School of Computer Science (SCS) administration, staff, and faculty members.</description></item><item><title>Personal Project Showcase</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-23-personal-project-showcase/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-23-personal-project-showcase/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Jackbox Jamboree</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-22-jackbox/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-22-jackbox/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Vulnerabilities in Web Apps</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-17-vulnerabilities-in-web-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-17-vulnerabilities-in-web-apps/</guid><description>Description On Wednesday, February 17, Robert Babaev gave a tech talk during dev club about web application security! Students learned how they could keep their website safe from SQL vulnerabilities, sensitive data exposure, and cross-site scripting.
To view a copy of the slides, click here!</description></item><item><title>Speed Friending</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-12-speed-friending/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/social/2021-02-12-speed-friending/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Rustlang Workshop</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-10-rustlang-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-10-rustlang-workshop/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Here for You Workshop</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/community/2021-02-08-here-for-you-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/community/2021-02-08-here-for-you-workshop/</guid><description>Description Do you want to be able to recognize and support your own mental health? Feeling overwhelmed and confused on how to take care of yourself during online school and a pandemic? Take a deep breath because the CCSS is here to support you!
On Monday, February 8th at 3 PM, we are bringing in the Carleton Health Promotion Team to give a workshop on mental health, self care, and where to find support!</description></item><item><title>Database Paradigms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-27-database-paradigms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-27-database-paradigms/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Declassified Online School Survival Guide</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/community/2021-01-22-survival-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/community/2021-01-22-survival-guide/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Finding your First Internship</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-16-finding-internships/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-16-finding-internships/</guid><description>Description Trying to find your first internship during this pandemic and feel like giving up? Don’t throw in the towel just yet! On Saturday, January 16th from 12 - 1 PM on our Discord, the CCSS is going to give you a quick crash course on how to land your first CS gig, even if you’re in your first year. The presentation slides can be viewed here!</description></item><item><title>Figma Workshop</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-13-figma-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-13-figma-workshop/</guid><description>Description Our very own Omar Flores is giving a Tech Talk introducing Figma on Wednesday, January 13th from 6-8 PM on Microsoft Teams! Figma is currently the most used design tool in tech from vector graphics and illustrations to buttons and design systems to prototypes. Come learn the basics of this incredible tool and how to begin building prototypes!
Omar is a third year Carleton CS student who&amp;rsquo;s worked as a software developer intern at Google, RBC and Deloitte :computer: He&amp;rsquo;s passionate about design and excited to show us the ropes on Wednesday so don&amp;rsquo;t miss out!</description></item><item><title>Advent of Code</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-12-01-advent-of-code/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-12-01-advent-of-code/</guid><description>Description This December, celebrate the holidays with Advent of Code!
Advent of Code is an Advent calendar of small programming puzzles that can be solved in any programming language you like.
This year, the CCSS will be hosting its own Advent of Code leaderboard and solutions repository! To join other participating Carleton CS students, login to Advent of Code and join using our unique leaderboard code: 970906-fa1dc2ae
Interested in sharing your solution?</description></item><item><title>Fall General Meeting</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/society/2020-11-27-fall-general-meeting/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/society/2020-11-27-fall-general-meeting/</guid><description>Description Slides Click here to view the meeting slides.</description></item><item><title>First Year Representative Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2020-09-27-first-year-rep-nominees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2020-09-27-first-year-rep-nominees/</guid><description>Election Candidate Platforms The CCSS Elections for 2021-2022 have begun! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce that we have 15 candidates running for positions on the board of directors.
$(document).ready(function(){ shuffle(); function shuffle(){ $(".people").each(function(){ var divs = $(this).find('div'); for(var i = 0; i Hey there first years! Thanks to everyone who has applied to run for first year representative with the CCSS, we have received your applications, and we will now be beginning the campaign period during which you can meet your representatives before voting begins.</description></item><item><title>First Year Representative Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2020-09-11-first-year-rep-nominations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2020-09-11-first-year-rep-nominations/</guid><description>The first-year rep positions are a chance for first-year students to take part in the governance of the CCSS. This means participating in internal meetings, being involved in the creation and planning of our events and initiatives, and having voting power in all important decisions for the year. If you would like to be a First-Year Representative, fill out the nomination form by Monday, September 21!
You can find the full election timeline and further details on the election policies outlined in our Writ of Election.</description></item><item><title>School is Back in Session</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2020-08-31-school-is-back-in-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2020-08-31-school-is-back-in-session/</guid><description>CS Clubs and Societies Info Sessions Are you an incoming or returning CS student looking to get involved this year, but not sure how? Well, look no further! The CCSS is collaborating with ALL clubs and societies affiliated with the School of Computer Science (SCS) to bring you an exciting, virtual CS Clubs &amp;amp; Societies Information Session! We will hold two identical sessions: one on Sunday, September 13 at 1:00 pm EDT and one on Saturday, September 19 at 9:00 am EDT.</description></item><item><title>Welcome Annoucement</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2020-07-15-welcome-annoucement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2020-07-15-welcome-annoucement/</guid><description>Hi! Welcome to the CCSS! Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re a new student, fresh out of high school and ready to start a new chapter of your life in university. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re a returning student, eager to get one year closer to graduating. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve done all of this before, and you&amp;rsquo;re coming back to school for a second degree. Whoever you are, the Carleton Computer Science Society welcomes you! We hope you will have a wonderful experience as you progress through your computer science degree, and we&amp;rsquo;re here to help make that happen!</description></item><item><title>Course Selection Webinar</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-07-05-course-selection-webinar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-07-05-course-selection-webinar/</guid><description>Description Hey Everyone! This past week the CCSS held multiple webinar sessions on helping incoming students register for courses. The presentation slides can be viewed here!</description></item><item><title>CCSS Election Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2019-2020/2020-03-02-ccss-election-platforms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2019-2020/2020-03-02-ccss-election-platforms/</guid><description>The Candidates are: President: William So Vice President: Jerry Liu Treasurer: Matthew MacRae-Bovell Director of Academics: Alexa de Grandmont Director of Social: Malcolm Smith Sarah Ali Director of Inclusion: Tiffany Lau The Campaign Platforms: William So - President: Hello everyone! It is my great pleasure to be running for CCSS President once again. In my three years of experience on the CCSS Board of Directors, I have amassed a varied skillset and informed insight on the way the society operates.</description></item><item><title>Happy Pride Month!</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/position/overlay/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/position/overlay/</guid><description>Step 1. Install Hugo Go to Hugo releases and download the appropriate version for your OS and architecture.
Save it somewhere specific as we will be using it in the next step.
More complete instructions are available at Install Hugo
Step 2. Build the Docs Hugo has its own example site which happens to also be the documentation site you are reading right now.
Follow the following steps:
Clone the Hugo repository Go into the repo Run hugo in server mode and build the docs Open your browser to http://localhost:1313 Corresponding pseudo commands:</description></item><item><title>First Year Representative 2019 Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2019-2020/2019-09-23-first-year-rep-2019-elections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2019-2020/2019-09-23-first-year-rep-2019-elections/</guid><description>Election Calendar:
Campaigning will take place from Monday Sept. 23 to Friday Sept. 27th Voting will take place from Saturday Sept. 28th to Wednesday Oct. 2nd Results will be announced on Saturday October 4th! The following are the representatives who are running for your first year representative:
Ujan Sen:
Hi everyone! I’m an international student from India and I’m excited to be a part of Carleton University and the CCSS.</description></item><item><title>CCSS Election for 2019-2020</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2019-03-15-ccss-elections-platforms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2019-03-15-ccss-elections-platforms/</guid><description>The Candidates are: President: William So Vice President: Matthew MacRae-Bovell Treasurer: Benjamin Karstad Director of Academics: Adam &amp;ldquo;Tennessee&amp;rdquo; Payzant Director of Social: Tiffany Lau Omar Garcia-Flores Director of Inclusion: Caleb Berry Faareha Khalid Anoushka Singhal The Campaign Platforms: William So - President: Throughout my academic career over the past two years at Carleton University, I have been heavily involved with the CCSS - as a First Year Representative last year, and as the current VP Social.</description></item><item><title>Changes to the Constitution</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2019-03-04-changes-to-the-constitution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2019-03-04-changes-to-the-constitution/</guid><description>The notable changes are:
The addition of a new elected position entitled &amp;ldquo;Director of Inclusion&amp;rdquo;, whose mandate is to promote and represent diversity initiatives within the society References to a new standing document entitled The Electoral Code, which establishes rules on how the CCSS general elections are to run each year Slight changes to formatting and wording to make the Constitution more readable, without altering the sense (except with the changes mentioned above) Linked below are the relevant documents.</description></item><item><title>First Year Representative Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2018-09-19-first-year-representative-elections/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2018-09-19-first-year-representative-elections/</guid><description>Election Calendar:
Campaigning will take place from Wednesday Sept. 19 to Monday Sept. 24th Voting will take place from Tuesday Sept. 24th to Friday Sept. 28th Results will be announced either on Saturday Sept. 29th or Sunday Sept. 30th The following are the representatives who are running for your first year representative:
Matthew MacRae-Bovell:
Hello, my name is Matthew MacRae - Bovell, and I&amp;rsquo;m a first year computer science student currently running for the position of CCSS first year representative.</description></item><item><title>CCSS Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2016-2017/2017-02-27-ccss-elections/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2016-2017/2017-02-27-ccss-elections/</guid><description>If you are looking for an opportunity to have a leadership role in the Computer Science Society, you should think about running as a director. There are four positions that you can run for: Vice President Vice President Social Vice President Academics Treasurer More details about the responsibilities of these roles are found in the nomination form.
To be nominated, you need to receive three signatures for other Computer Science students OR one signature from a current director of the CCSS.</description></item><item><title>First Year Rep Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2018-09-06-first-year-rep-elections/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2018-09-06-first-year-rep-elections/</guid><description>Hey, first-years!
You may have heard some talk over the past few days about first year reps. But what is a first year rep, and what does it entail to hold one such position? For the CCSS, First Year Reps are the voice of the first-year students in computer science. They help advertise our events to new students, and they can run events and initiatives of their own as well. First Year Reps are members of the CCSS Board of Directors, and get to have a say on all important decisions.</description></item><item><title>VP WiCS Announcement</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2018-09-08-vp-wics-announcement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2018-2019/2018-09-08-vp-wics-announcement/</guid><description>Over the past few months, the Board of Directors of the CCSS has been discussing the possibility of creating a new position to collaborate with the WiCS (Women in Computer Science) group on campus. We are pleased to announce that we will be welcoming a new position to the CCSS, VP WiCS!
The CCSS hopes to place a bigger importance on diversity efforts in the following years to come. VP WiCS will be a dedicated a position on the Board of Directors that will lead these diversity efforts, ensuring the events and atmosphere of the computer science society is welcoming and inclusive.</description></item><item><title>Course Selection Webinar</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2016-2017/2017-01-25-scala-talk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2016-2017/2017-01-25-scala-talk/</guid><description>Description Scala is modern, strongly, statically typed, object-functional programming language. In this workshop, we will look at how Scala helps us write safe and performant code while maintaining high level of productivity. Furthermore, we will talk about the Scala ecosystem.
Speaker: Petro Verkhogliad</description></item><item><title>Christmas Party</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2016-2017/2016-12-01-christmas-party/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/events/2016-2017/2016-12-01-christmas-party/</guid><description>Description SExams are near but so are the holidays. Join us on December 1st for our Annual Christmas Party. There will be food to share, gingerbread cookies to decorate, music to sing along to and many games to play.</description></item><item><title>Lab and Study Space Concerns</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2016-2017/2016-11-17-study-spaces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2016-2017/2016-11-17-study-spaces/</guid><description>We have scheduled a meeting with the School of Computer Science on January 3rd, 2017 where we plan to bring up all of your comments. To ensure we don&amp;rsquo;t forget anything, please write down any comments or concerns you have in this document and we will do our best to fix it.
Some concerns we plan to address:
More Lab and Study Spaces: Quite and/or collaborative study spaces that do not hold tutorials during the day.</description></item><item><title>Apply to be a First Year Rep!</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2016-2017/2016-09-14-first_year_reps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2016-2017/2016-09-14-first_year_reps/</guid><description>What is a First Year Rep?
First Year Reps are elected positions (that&amp;rsquo;s right, first years will need to vote for their two reps) for first years to get a chance to be a part of the CCSS board of directors. They represent all of the CS first years at meetings and help advertise our events.
Their role includes:
Representing first year computer science students Attend meetings of the board Advertise events to first year students Run their own initiatives and/or events Perks:</description></item><item><title>The Week of Awesome!</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2016-2017/2016-09-01-week-of-awesome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2016-2017/2016-09-01-week-of-awesome/</guid><description>The Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS) will be running a week of awesome events for computer science students the second week of school. Think of it as a way for students to get engaged with the people who are in their classes along with their professors in a more computer science- specific setting. Here are the details:
Monday, September 12th at 2:30pm: Coffee Social This event will be a great place to chat with your fellow students and faculty and have some free coffee and snacks!</description></item></channel></rss>