<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>news on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/</link><description>Recent content in news on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Happy Pride Month!</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2021-2022/2021-06-14-happy-pride-month/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2021-2022/2021-06-14-happy-pride-month/</guid><description>From all of us at the CCSS, happy pride month!
Here is a list of amazing resources for LGBTQIA2S+:
Carleton&amp;rsquo;s Women in Computer Science Pride Series on Instagram Gender &amp;amp; Sexuality Resource Centre LGBT YouthLine The Trevor Project</description></item><item><title>Winter 2021 Feedback and Suggestions Survey Results</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2021-2022/2021-06-04-winter-feedback-survey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2021-2022/2021-06-04-winter-feedback-survey/</guid><description>As elected student representatives of the Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS), it is important that undergraduate computer science students under the School of Computer Science (SCS), studying at Carleton University, have their voices heard through channels that they can trust.
Due to COVID-19, many students have expressed concerns regarding challenges in an online learning environment. Similar to the Fall 2020 SCS Undergraduate Feedback &amp;amp; Suggestions Survey that was created for computer science students to share their experiences and opinions regarding online courses with the School of Computer Science (SCS) administration, staff, and faculty members (that report can be found here and the password was sent to all B.</description></item><item><title>CCSS X SCS Feedback and Suggestions Survey</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-04-04-winter-feedback-survey/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-04-04-winter-feedback-survey/</guid><description>As we’re nearing the end of the Winter term, how was this term compared to the Fall term? Was it better, worse, or the same? What did you find challenging?
The Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS) wants to hear from you! It is important to us that students have their voices heard through channels that they can trust and are comfortable with. As the elected student representatives this school year, we have many opportunities to share student experiences and opinions with the School of Computer Science (SCS) and its faculty members, including teaching staff.</description></item><item><title>Board of Directors Election Results 2021-2022</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-03-30-election-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-03-30-election-results/</guid><description>Congratulations to our upcoming Board of Director members, and thank you to all candidates for getting involved with the CCSS! A complete breakdown of the election results can be seen in the PDF here!
The 2021-2022 CCSS board will be as follows:
President:
Sarah Ali Vice President:
Erica Li Director of Finance:
Victor Li Director of Academics:
Matthew MacRae-Bovell Director of Social:</description></item><item><title>Election Candidate Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-03-14-election-platforms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/ccss-website/news/2020-2021/2021-03-14-election-platforms/</guid><description>Election Candidate Platforms The CCSS Elections for 2021-2022 have begun! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce that we have 15 candidates running for positions on the board of directors.
$(document).ready(function(){ shuffle(); function shuffle(){ $(".president").each(function(){ var divs = $(this).find('div'); for(var i = 0; i The Candidates are: President: Sarah Ali William So Vice President: Ayodeji Akinbile Erica Li Malcolm Smith Director of Finance: Benjamin Karstad Victor Li Director of Academics: Aaditya (Adi) Chopra Matthew MacRae-Bovell Robert Babaev Director of Social: Jerry Liu Milo Goodfellow Veronica Yung Director of Community: Patrick Ene Zara Ali Sarah Ali - President I’m currently serving as a Communications Officer on the Board of Directors and I’m excited to have a chance to lead the new board into the future of the CCSS for the next academic year!</description></item></channel></rss>