<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>news on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/</link><description>Recent content in news on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Our new Logo</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/our-new-logo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/our-new-logo/</guid><description>With our return to in-person activity this year, we really thought it was finally time to give the CCSS a new coat of paint. After quite a lot of variation, we&amp;rsquo;re proud to present a symbol that we believe represents our program, community, and our mission as an organization.
Why we needed a new logo Although we loved our previous logo very dearly, there were some issues with its design.</description></item><item><title>CCSS General Election Results 2022-2023</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/election-results-2022-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/election-results-2022-2023/</guid><description>A complete breakdown of the election results can be seen in the PDF here.
The 2022-2023 CCSS Board of Directors will be as follows:
President:
Matthew MacRae-Bovell Vice President:
Forest Anderson Director of Finance:
Victor Li Director of Academics:
Amelie Haefele Director of Social:
Aaditya Chopra (Adi) Director of Community:
As no candidates ran for this position in this year&amp;rsquo;s election, the Director of Community will be appointed by the new Board of Directors in the upcoming academic year.</description></item><item><title>CCSS General Election Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections-2022-2023/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections-2022-2023/</guid><description>The CCSS Elections for 2022-2023 have begun! We’re excited to announce that we have 8 candidates running for positions on the Board of Directors.</description></item><item><title>CCSS General Elections 2022-2023</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2022-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2022-2023/</guid><description>The Board consists of the following six positions:
President Vice President Director of Finance Director of Academics Director of Social Director of Community Here is the breakdown of this year&amp;rsquo;s electoral period:
Nomination Period: February 28 - March 6 Campaigning Period: March 10 - March 20 Voting Period: March 21 - March 23 If you want to run for a CCSS Board of Directors position for the 2022-2023 academic year, please fill out the Nomination Form here.</description></item><item><title>CCSS Development Mentorship Program</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/ccss-development-mentorship-program/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/ccss-development-mentorship-program/</guid><description>Applications now open!
Have you been meaning to start developing your own projects but have no idea how to start or keep going? Or maybe you’ve already been dabbling on projects and want to share your experience and insight with programmers who are starting out? You can now apply to become a development mentor or mentee! Applications are open until end of day January 26th.
Mentor Application Mentee Application
What does a mentor do?</description></item><item><title>CCSS 2021-2022 Hoodie</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2021-2021-hoodie/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2021-2021-hoodie/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s official! We are now accepting orders for our new 2021-2022 hoodie until December 31st. Orders can be placed on the CCSS Shopify store. The expected pickup date for your order will be mid to late January. Orders will only be shipped to Carleton University and will have to be picked up at the CCSS Lounge (Herzberg 4135). YYou will receive an email with more information closer to the shipment date.</description></item><item><title>First Year Representative Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/first-year-rep-platforms-2021/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/first-year-rep-platforms-2021/</guid><description/></item><item><title>First Year Representative Nominations</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/first-year-rep-nominations/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/first-year-rep-nominations/</guid><description>The Carleton Computer Science Society is looking for two first year CS students to join our Board of Directors as First Year Representatives for the academic year 2021-2022. Nominations are now open here!
The first-year rep positions are a chance for freshmen to take part in our governance and make a direct impact on our society. This means participating in internal meetings, being involved in the creation and planning of our events and initiatives and having voting power on all our decisions!</description></item><item><title>Become a Tech Talk Presenter!</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/fall-2021-tech-talk-signup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/fall-2021-tech-talk-signup/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in becoming a speaker, please fill out this form. If you are interested in giving a Tech Talk during September, please complete this form before September 1st.
We are looking for students of all experience levels and year standings (including incoming first years) who are interested in giving presentations. No prior presentation or tech talk experience is required.
Your presentation could discuss a personal project, new technology, work experience, research, or really anything you&amp;rsquo;ve learned that you feel would be beneficial to your fellow computer science students.</description></item><item><title>Hoodie Design Contest</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2021-2022/2021-07-27-hoodie-design-contest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jul 2021 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2021-2022/2021-07-27-hoodie-design-contest/</guid><description>The CCSS is giving you an opportunity to show off your skills and submit a graphic to be featured on the back of the official CCSS hoodie this year. The winner will receive a free hoodie with their design on the back!
Rules of this contest are as follows:
All designs must be related to the CCSS, Carleton University, and/or computer science No copyrighted images/designs Submitted designs must have a transparent background Designs should work well with a dark gray background (#36454f) PNG files of your design can be submitted here from July 28th to the end of August 18th: https://forms.</description></item><item><title>Happy Pride Month!</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2021-2022/2021-06-14-happy-pride-month/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Jun 2021 23:11:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2021-2022/2021-06-14-happy-pride-month/</guid><description>From all of us at the CCSS, happy pride month!
Here is a list of amazing resources for LGBTQIA2S+:
Carleton&amp;rsquo;s Women in Computer Science Pride Series on Instagram Gender &amp;amp; Sexuality Resource Centre LGBT YouthLine The Trevor Project</description></item><item><title>Winter 2021 Feedback and Suggestions Survey Results</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2021-2022/2021-06-04-winter-feedback-survey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2021-2022/2021-06-04-winter-feedback-survey/</guid><description>As elected student representatives of the Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS), it is important that undergraduate computer science students under the School of Computer Science (SCS), studying at Carleton University, have their voices heard through channels that they can trust.
Due to COVID-19, many students have expressed concerns regarding challenges in an online learning environment. Similar to the Fall 2020 SCS Undergraduate Feedback &amp;amp; Suggestions Survey that was created for computer science students to share their experiences and opinions regarding online courses with the School of Computer Science (SCS) administration, staff, and faculty members (that report can be found here and the password was sent to all B.</description></item><item><title>CCSS X SCS Feedback and Suggestions Survey</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-04-04-winter-feedback-survey/</link><pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-04-04-winter-feedback-survey/</guid><description>As we’re nearing the end of the Winter term, how was this term compared to the Fall term? Was it better, worse, or the same? What did you find challenging?
The Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS) wants to hear from you! It is important to us that students have their voices heard through channels that they can trust and are comfortable with. As the elected student representatives this school year, we have many opportunities to share student experiences and opinions with the School of Computer Science (SCS) and its faculty members, including teaching staff.</description></item><item><title>Board of Directors Election Results 2021-2022</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-03-30-election-results/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-03-30-election-results/</guid><description>Congratulations to our upcoming Board of Director members, and thank you to all candidates for getting involved with the CCSS! A complete breakdown of the election results can be seen in the PDF here!
The 2021-2022 CCSS board will be as follows:
President:
Sarah Ali Vice President:
Erica Li Director of Finance:
Victor Li Director of Academics:
Matthew MacRae-Bovell Director of Social:</description></item><item><title>Election Candidate Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-03-14-election-platforms/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-03-14-election-platforms/</guid><description>Election Candidate Platforms The CCSS Elections for 2021-2022 have begun! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce that we have 15 candidates running for positions on the board of directors.
$(document).ready(function(){ shuffle(); function shuffle(){ $(".president").each(function(){ var divs = $(this).find('div'); for(var i = 0; i The Candidates are: President: Sarah Ali William So Vice President: Ayodeji Akinbile Erica Li Malcolm Smith Director of Finance: Benjamin Karstad Victor Li Director of Academics: Aaditya (Adi) Chopra Matthew MacRae-Bovell Robert Babaev Director of Social: Jerry Liu Milo Goodfellow Veronica Yung Director of Community: Patrick Ene Zara Ali Sarah Ali - President I’m currently serving as a Communications Officer on the Board of Directors and I’m excited to have a chance to lead the new board into the future of the CCSS for the next academic year!</description></item><item><title>CCSS Elections 2021</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-02-26-elections/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-02-26-elections/</guid><description>There are six positions to run for:
President Vice President Director of Finance Director of Academics Director of Social Director of Community You can find the full election timeline and further details on the electoral policies outlined in our Writ of Election.
Interested in running for a position? Fill out the nomination form by Wednesday, March 3.
Please contact elections@ccss.carleton.ca with any questions or concerns regarding the CCSS elections.</description></item><item><title>Fall Feedback and Suggestions Survey Report</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-02-24-fall-feedback-survey/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2021-02-24-fall-feedback-survey/</guid><description>As elected student representatives of the Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS), it is important that undergraduate computer science students under the School of Computer Science (SCS), studying at Carleton University, have their voices heard through channels that they can trust.
Due to COVID-19 in 2020, many students have expressed concerns regarding challenges in an online learning environment. Therefore, Tiffany Lau (the 2020-2021 Director of Community) and William So (the 2020-2021 President) have created an SCS Undergraduate Feedback &amp;amp; Suggestions Survey for computer science students to share their experiences and opinions regarding online courses this term with the School of Computer Science (SCS) administration, staff, and faculty members.</description></item><item><title>First Year Representative Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2020-09-27-first-year-rep-nominees/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2020-09-27-first-year-rep-nominees/</guid><description>Election Candidate Platforms The CCSS Elections for 2021-2022 have begun! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce that we have 15 candidates running for positions on the board of directors.
$(document).ready(function(){ shuffle(); function shuffle(){ $(".people").each(function(){ var divs = $(this).find('div'); for(var i = 0; i Hey there first years! Thanks to everyone who has applied to run for first year representative with the CCSS, we have received your applications, and we will now be beginning the campaign period during which you can meet your representatives before voting begins.</description></item><item><title>First Year Representative Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2020-09-11-first-year-rep-nominations/</link><pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2020-09-11-first-year-rep-nominations/</guid><description>The first-year rep positions are a chance for first-year students to take part in the governance of the CCSS. This means participating in internal meetings, being involved in the creation and planning of our events and initiatives, and having voting power in all important decisions for the year. If you would like to be a First-Year Representative, fill out the nomination form by Monday, September 21!
You can find the full election timeline and further details on the election policies outlined in our Writ of Election.</description></item><item><title>School is Back in Session</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2020-08-31-school-is-back-in-session/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2020-08-31-school-is-back-in-session/</guid><description>CS Clubs and Societies Info Sessions Are you an incoming or returning CS student looking to get involved this year, but not sure how? Well, look no further! The CCSS is collaborating with ALL clubs and societies affiliated with the School of Computer Science (SCS) to bring you an exciting, virtual CS Clubs &amp;amp; Societies Information Session! We will hold two identical sessions: one on Sunday, September 13 at 1:00 pm EDT and one on Saturday, September 19 at 9:00 am EDT.</description></item><item><title>Welcome Annoucement</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2020-07-15-welcome-annoucement/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2020-2021/2020-07-15-welcome-annoucement/</guid><description>Hi! Welcome to the CCSS! Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re a new student, fresh out of high school and ready to start a new chapter of your life in university. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;re a returning student, eager to get one year closer to graduating. Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve done all of this before, and you&amp;rsquo;re coming back to school for a second degree. Whoever you are, the Carleton Computer Science Society welcomes you! We hope you will have a wonderful experience as you progress through your computer science degree, and we&amp;rsquo;re here to help make that happen!</description></item><item><title>CCSS Election Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2019-2020/2020-03-02-ccss-election-platforms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2019-2020/2020-03-02-ccss-election-platforms/</guid><description>The Candidates are: President: William So Vice President: Jerry Liu Treasurer: Matthew MacRae-Bovell Director of Academics: Alexa de Grandmont Director of Social: Malcolm Smith Sarah Ali Director of Inclusion: Tiffany Lau The Campaign Platforms: William So - President: Hello everyone! It is my great pleasure to be running for CCSS President once again. In my three years of experience on the CCSS Board of Directors, I have amassed a varied skillset and informed insight on the way the society operates.</description></item><item><title>First Year Representative 2019 Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2019-2020/2019-09-23-first-year-rep-2019-elections/</link><pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2019-2020/2019-09-23-first-year-rep-2019-elections/</guid><description>Election Calendar:
Campaigning will take place from Monday Sept. 23 to Friday Sept. 27th Voting will take place from Saturday Sept. 28th to Wednesday Oct. 2nd Results will be announced on Saturday October 4th! The following are the representatives who are running for your first year representative:
Ujan Sen:
Hi everyone! I’m an international student from India and I’m excited to be a part of Carleton University and the CCSS.</description></item><item><title>CCSS Election for 2019-2020</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2019-03-15-ccss-elections-platforms/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2019-03-15-ccss-elections-platforms/</guid><description>The Candidates are: President: William So Vice President: Matthew MacRae-Bovell Treasurer: Benjamin Karstad Director of Academics: Adam &amp;ldquo;Tennessee&amp;rdquo; Payzant Director of Social: Tiffany Lau Omar Garcia-Flores Director of Inclusion: Caleb Berry Faareha Khalid Anoushka Singhal The Campaign Platforms: William So - President: Throughout my academic career over the past two years at Carleton University, I have been heavily involved with the CCSS - as a First Year Representative last year, and as the current VP Social.</description></item><item><title>Changes to the Constitution</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2019-03-04-changes-to-the-constitution/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2019-03-04-changes-to-the-constitution/</guid><description>The notable changes are:
The addition of a new elected position entitled &amp;ldquo;Director of Inclusion&amp;rdquo;, whose mandate is to promote and represent diversity initiatives within the society References to a new standing document entitled The Electoral Code, which establishes rules on how the CCSS general elections are to run each year Slight changes to formatting and wording to make the Constitution more readable, without altering the sense (except with the changes mentioned above) Linked below are the relevant documents.</description></item><item><title>First Year Representative Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2018-09-19-first-year-representative-elections/</link><pubDate>Wed, 19 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2018-09-19-first-year-representative-elections/</guid><description>Election Calendar:
Campaigning will take place from Wednesday Sept. 19 to Monday Sept. 24th Voting will take place from Tuesday Sept. 24th to Friday Sept. 28th Results will be announced either on Saturday Sept. 29th or Sunday Sept. 30th The following are the representatives who are running for your first year representative:
Matthew MacRae-Bovell:
Hello, my name is Matthew MacRae - Bovell, and I&amp;rsquo;m a first year computer science student currently running for the position of CCSS first year representative.</description></item><item><title>CCSS Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2016-2017/2017-02-27-ccss-elections/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2016-2017/2017-02-27-ccss-elections/</guid><description>If you are looking for an opportunity to have a leadership role in the Computer Science Society, you should think about running as a director. There are four positions that you can run for: Vice President Vice President Social Vice President Academics Treasurer More details about the responsibilities of these roles are found in the nomination form.
To be nominated, you need to receive three signatures for other Computer Science students OR one signature from a current director of the CCSS.</description></item><item><title>First Year Rep Elections</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2018-09-06-first-year-rep-elections/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2018-09-06-first-year-rep-elections/</guid><description>Hey, first-years!
You may have heard some talk over the past few days about first year reps. But what is a first year rep, and what does it entail to hold one such position? For the CCSS, First Year Reps are the voice of the first-year students in computer science. They help advertise our events to new students, and they can run events and initiatives of their own as well. First Year Reps are members of the CCSS Board of Directors, and get to have a say on all important decisions.</description></item><item><title>VP WiCS Announcement</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2018-09-08-vp-wics-announcement/</link><pubDate>Sat, 08 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2018-2019/2018-09-08-vp-wics-announcement/</guid><description>Over the past few months, the Board of Directors of the CCSS has been discussing the possibility of creating a new position to collaborate with the WiCS (Women in Computer Science) group on campus. We are pleased to announce that we will be welcoming a new position to the CCSS, VP WiCS!
The CCSS hopes to place a bigger importance on diversity efforts in the following years to come. VP WiCS will be a dedicated a position on the Board of Directors that will lead these diversity efforts, ensuring the events and atmosphere of the computer science society is welcoming and inclusive.</description></item><item><title>Lab and Study Space Concerns</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2016-2017/2016-11-17-study-spaces/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2016-2017/2016-11-17-study-spaces/</guid><description>We have scheduled a meeting with the School of Computer Science on January 3rd, 2017 where we plan to bring up all of your comments. To ensure we don&amp;rsquo;t forget anything, please write down any comments or concerns you have in this document and we will do our best to fix it.
Some concerns we plan to address:
More Lab and Study Spaces: Quite and/or collaborative study spaces that do not hold tutorials during the day.</description></item><item><title>Apply to be a First Year Rep!</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2016-2017/2016-09-14-first_year_reps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2016-2017/2016-09-14-first_year_reps/</guid><description>What is a First Year Rep?
First Year Reps are elected positions (that&amp;rsquo;s right, first years will need to vote for their two reps) for first years to get a chance to be a part of the CCSS board of directors. They represent all of the CS first years at meetings and help advertise our events.
Their role includes:
Representing first year computer science students Attend meetings of the board Advertise events to first year students Run their own initiatives and/or events Perks:</description></item><item><title>The Week of Awesome!</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2016-2017/2016-09-01-week-of-awesome/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/2016-2017/2016-09-01-week-of-awesome/</guid><description>The Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS) will be running a week of awesome events for computer science students the second week of school. Think of it as a way for students to get engaged with the people who are in their classes along with their professors in a more computer science- specific setting. Here are the details:
Monday, September 12th at 2:30pm: Coffee Social This event will be a great place to chat with your fellow students and faculty and have some free coffee and snacks!</description></item></channel></rss>