<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Community on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/community/</link><description>Recent content in Community on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/community/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Here for You Workshop</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2021-02-08-here-for-you-workshop/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2021-02-08-here-for-you-workshop/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Do you want to be able to recognize and support your own mental health? Feeling overwhelmed and confused on how to take care of yourself during online school and a pandemic? Take a deep breath because the CCSS is here to support you!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On Monday, February 8th at 3 PM, we are bringing in the Carleton Health Promotion Team to give a workshop on mental health, self care, and where to find support! Take some time out just for yourself and join us by registering for the event here: &lt;a href="https://bit.ly/here-for-you-registration">https://bit.ly/here-for-you-registration&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Declassified Online School Survival Guide</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2021-01-22-survival-guide/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2021-01-22-survival-guide/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Prof Social</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-11-13-prof-social/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-11-13-prof-social/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>One of the most popular recurring CCSS events is Prof Night - where we have historically invited SCS faculty to socialize with students at Mike&amp;rsquo;s Place Pub on campus.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since we can&amp;rsquo;t meet in-person, this year&amp;rsquo;s version of Prof Night will be taking place on Zoom!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Students and faculty members will have a chance to mingle with one another in a number of breakout rooms. We have also invited the Fall Carleton CS graduating cohort to join us and commemorate their success!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Equity &amp; Inclusion</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-11-12-equity-and-inclusion/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-11-12-equity-and-inclusion/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Do you want to learn more about equity, inclusion and how student communities can strive to empower everybody? Come learn with the CCSS on Thursday, November 12 from 12 – 1 PM EST! We’re attending an Equity and Inclusion Workshop hosted by the Carleton Department of Equity and Inclusive Communities over Zoom. We’re going to be looking at scenarios where we can apply our knowledge, engage with concepts and advance our awareness of what it means to be equitable and inclusive. Hope to see you there! ⭐️&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CS Clubs and Societies Info Session</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-09-19-cs-clubs-and-societies-info-session/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-09-19-cs-clubs-and-societies-info-session/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Are you an incoming or returning CS student looking to get involved this year, but not sure how?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, look no further! To kick off (and close off) this year’s CCSS Week of Awesome, we are collaborating with ALL clubs and societies affiliated with the School of Computer Science (SCS) to bring you an exciting, virtual CS Clubs &amp;amp; Societies Information Session!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This info session will be happening on Sunday, September 13 @ 1:00 pm EDT and Saturday, September 19 @ 9:00 am EDT.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Week of Awesome: Work Your Space - Computer Setup Talk</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-09-16-work-your-space/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-09-16-work-your-space/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>For school this year, we will all be spending hours on end sitting in our rooms in front of our computers - whether it be for virtual lectures, coursework, or studying. So why not make that experience the best it could possibly be? The CCSS wants you to succeed in your studies, and that means making sure your workspace works for you! At this Week of Awesome Talk, we will cover the basics of desktop organization, ergonomics, and good work habits to keep you physically and mentally healthy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Week of Awesome: Sh*t I Wish I Knew</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-09-14-wish-i-knew/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-09-14-wish-i-knew/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Don&amp;rsquo;t know what to expect out of your first year in Carleton Computer Science? Don&amp;rsquo;t panic, because the CCSS Week of Awesome has got you covered with our annual instalment of Sh*t I Wish I Knew! We&amp;rsquo;ll give you our tips and tricks for everything from choosing your courses to building good study habits, managing your time and how to succeed as a remote student. Come listen to our upper-year students tell you all their advice on thriving in first year and all the things they wish someone had told them when they were in your shoes!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CS Clubs and Societies Info Session</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-09-13-cs-clubs-and-societies-info-session/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-09-13-cs-clubs-and-societies-info-session/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Are you an incoming or returning CS student looking to get involved this year, but not sure how?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Well, look no further! To kick off (and close off) this year’s CCSS Week of Awesome, we are collaborating with ALL clubs and societies affiliated with the School of Computer Science (SCS) to bring you an exciting, virtual CS Clubs &amp;amp; Societies Information Session!&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>This info session will be happening on Sunday, September 13 @ 1:00 pm EDT and Saturday, September 19 @ 9:00 am EDT.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>From Faraway Q&amp;A</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-09-07-international-student-panel/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/community/2020-09-07-international-student-panel/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Are you an international student coming to Carleton for the first time this year? Whether you&amp;rsquo;re here for a short time on exchange or starting the multi-year journey of completing a degree, the CCSS wants you to feel welcomed in our community!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please join us on Monday, September 7 from 9:30 AM to 11:00 AM EDT to attend a panel of fellow international students ranging from 2nd to 4th year, who chose to study computer science at Carleton, just like you! They will be talking about their experiences as international students in CS and answering any questions or concerns that you may have :yellow_heart:! We will also have a representative from the International Student Services Office (ISSO) who will be doing a short presentation on all the resources Carleton has to offer you :clap:!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCSS Textbook Sale</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/community/2020-02-03-textbook-sale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/community/2020-02-03-textbook-sale/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Gather up your spare change, because the CCSS is having its textbook sale once again! We&amp;rsquo;ll be set up all day on the 4th floor of Herzberg Laboratories, next to the main staircase. All books will be available for $5 or less!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCSS x WiCS Potluck</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/social/2019-11-29-ccss-wics-potluck/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/social/2019-11-29-ccss-wics-potluck/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>CCSS and WiCS are partnering up to organize a lunch potluck event, open to students, faculty and staff! Join us for a casual social gathering with great food!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Feel free to bring something so that there’s enough for everyone to share (non-junk food preferred)! There will be access to a microwave oven in case you need to heat your dish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please let us know what you’re bringing in this spreadsheet: &lt;a href="https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1O20M_izR-X7w6DKGVZXuWslYZzcFm5QMdQZQme_OKv4/edit?fbclid=IwAR1lTlcrTB2zZQilEKfjnXb4PfWH9efQogmi5FbCWAXXidT9lOaYViEcFRY#gid=0">https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1O20M_izR-X7w6DKGVZXuWslYZzcFm5QMdQZQme_OKv4/edit?fbclid=IwAR1lTlcrTB2zZQilEKfjnXb4PfWH9efQogmi5FbCWAXXidT9lOaYViEcFRY#gid=0&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Week of Awesome: Sh*t I Wish I Knew</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2019-09-11-i-wish-i-knew/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2019-09-11-i-wish-i-knew/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Hello first years! Come learn from some of the mistakes and pitfalls that upper year students made when they were in their first year.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCSS x WiCS Potluck</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2018-2019/social/2019-03-19-ccss-wics-potluck/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2018-2019/social/2019-03-19-ccss-wics-potluck/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The CCSS and WiCS are partnering up to organize a lunch potluck event, open to students, faculty and staff. Join us on March 19, from noon to 2 pm, for a casual social gathering with great food!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All attendees must bring something to share (non-junk food preferred). There will be access to a microwave oven, in case you need to heat your dish.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>See you there!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCSS Professional Headshot Day</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2018-2019/community/2018-11-28-professional-headshot-day/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2018-2019/community/2018-11-28-professional-headshot-day/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s just like high school picture day all over again! We&amp;rsquo;ll have a semi-professional photography setup with our own professional photographer to take the picture you need for your website or Linkedin profile.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All images will be uploaded to a Google Drive folder and will be accessible to the public.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>WiCS Breakfast Meet &amp; Greet</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2018-2019/social/2018-11-16-wics-breakfast-meet-and-greet/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2018-2019/social/2018-11-16-wics-breakfast-meet-and-greet/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Come on out and hear about some experiences from CAN-CWiC and the Grace Hopper Celebration, grab some swag from these events (limited quantities), and meet the new WiCS Officer for CCSS.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Light breakfast (coffee, tea, juice, bagels croissants, maybe smoked salmon, etc) will be provided from 9:30am to 10:00am.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCSS Textbook Sale</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2018-2019/community/2018-09-26-textbook-sale/</link><pubDate>Wed, 26 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2018-2019/community/2018-09-26-textbook-sale/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s time for our biannual textbook sale! Stop by the Herzberg 4th floor stairwell to grab some textbooks on the cheap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The price of the textbooks will range from $1 to $10. We can take cash or credit!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Note: These are not course textbooks, but rather general topic notebooks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Diversity in Engineering and Technology Networking Evening</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2017-2018/community/2018-01-23-diversity-in-tech-networking/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2017-2018/community/2018-01-23-diversity-in-tech-networking/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Registration is open on mySuccess!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As part of an exciting week of career-related programming, Co-op and Career Services and our presenting sponsor, Ericsson, are pleased to host a networking evening celebrating Diversity in Engineering and Technology!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This event will allow co-op students and new graduates from underrepresented groups to meet and mingle with employers from engineering and IT-related firms who are dedicated to creating a diverse workforce. Meet representatives from a range of engineering and IT firms and hear about their exciting plans for the future and their commitment to inclusion and diversity.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>CCSS Book Sale</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2017-2018/community/2018-01-17-book-sale/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2017-2018/community/2018-01-17-book-sale/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Great Computer Science books at amazing prices! Learn a new skill, study for a class, or just enjoy yourself!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Donations of books in advance toward the sale are appreciated and welcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Funds raised at the sale will go toward future CCSS events and efforts.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Textbook Sale</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2017-2018/community/2017-09-18-textbook-sale/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2017-2018/community/2017-09-18-textbook-sale/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Want to get a good deal on computer science and math textbooks? Join us for our second biannual Textbook Sale on Sept 18th! We will have a wide range of textbooks covering topics such as Discrete Structures, Calculus, Linear Algebra, C++, Game Dev and so much more. Our prices range from as low as $1 to $30.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Textbook Sale</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2016-2017/community/2017-01-10-textbook-sale/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2016-2017/community/2017-01-10-textbook-sale/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="description">Description&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Want to get a good deal on computer science and math textbooks? Join us for our first annual Textbook Sale on January 10th! We will have a wide range of textbooks covering topics such as Discrete Structures, Calculus, Linear Algebra, C++ and so much more. Our prices range from as low as $1 to $20.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>