<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Talks on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/talks/</link><description>Recent content in Talks on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/talks/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Finding Internships</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2022-01-13-finding-internships/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2022-01-13-finding-internships/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Is React the next JQuery?</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-12-16-is-react-the-next-jquery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-12-16-is-react-the-next-jquery/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Your First Database</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-11-10-your-first-database/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-11-10-your-first-database/</guid><description>Description Your First Database is a beginner friendly workshop that will teach you how to build and interface with your first database management system using Python.</description></item><item><title>Introduction To GraphQL</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-11-04-introduction-to-graphql/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-11-04-introduction-to-graphql/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Your First Website</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-10-20-your-first-website/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-10-20-your-first-website/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Internet Security: How Simple Math keeps your Password Safe</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-10-06-how-simple-math-keeps-your-password-safe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-10-06-how-simple-math-keeps-your-password-safe/</guid><description>Description Join Morley Abbott, a Software Developer who formerly worked on AWS Identity and Access Management, for a talk on internet security! Learn how the S in HTTPS works and the math behind why it&amp;rsquo;s safe.</description></item><item><title>Navigating a New Career</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-09-29-navigating-a-new-career/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-09-29-navigating-a-new-career/</guid><description>Navigating a New Career Join two new Carleton grads Aarthi Ganesh and Abhi Santhosh as they unpack their ‘lessons learned’ navigating a new career as software developers at Martello Technologies. Find out what surprised them when they started and how their time at Carleton prepped them for what was next. Spoiler alert, their top tip is: “You don’t even know what you don’t know.”</description></item><item><title>Inferring the Algorithms Used by Different Processes Using Machine Learning</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/inferring-the-algorithms-used-by-different-processes/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/inferring-the-algorithms-used-by-different-processes/</guid><description>Abstract: Some natural and human-engineered processes exhibit patterns that suggest an underlying algorithm. For natural processes, this could be thought of as the biochemical processes dictated by genes or other natural forces. For human-engineered processes, such algorithms represent either memetic thought within a culture or the physical limitations and requirements for human use. This research has examined inferring the algorithms used by such processes from data observed over time. For example, taking a sequence of photos of a plant as it grows can be used to infer the algorithm used by the plant to grow.</description></item><item><title>Your First Web Service</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-09-15-your-first-web-service/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Sep 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-09-15-your-first-web-service/</guid><description>Description &amp;ldquo;Your First Web Service&amp;rdquo; is a beginner friendly workshop that will teach you how to build your first web service using Python and Fast API.</description></item><item><title>Lightning Talks</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-09-13-lightning-talks/</link><pubDate>Mon, 13 Sep 2021 16:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2021-2022/2021-09-13-lightning-talks/</guid><description>Description Get ready for our first virtual tech talks of the fall semester!
With the help of our amazing student presenters, will be ending off the Monday of our Week of Awesome with three back-to-back Lightning Talks!
Each talk will last 10-20 minutes and tackle topics such as internet security, software development, and much much more.
Be sure to join us via Zoom on September 13th @ 6:30 PM EDT for a fun filled evening of presentations.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain + Crypto Q&amp;A Session</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-04-07-blockchain-crypto-qa-session/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-04-07-blockchain-crypto-qa-session/</guid><description>Description We have invited Jeremy Clark, an associate professor at the Concordia Institute for Information Systems Engineering, back for an interactive Q&amp;amp;A session to continue the discussion on crypto and blockchain technology!
Given that there were many audience questions left unanswered during his previous lecture, and many of you expressed interest in having Jeremy back, we are very happy to be hosting this follow-up discussion session.</description></item><item><title>Become a Senior Engineer in 2 years</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-24-become-a-senior-developer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-24-become-a-senior-developer/</guid><description>Description Ryan Latta will be talking about what it takes to become a Senior level engineer! This talk will discuss what qualities make a great Senior Developer, and what you can start learning and practicing today that will help you become a Senior Engineer within 2 years of starting your career!
Ryan Latta has been in the software industry for over a decade. He has worked launching his own start-ups and in Fortune 100 companies doing everything from software development to acting as a CTO.</description></item><item><title>Blockchain and Cryptocurrency Landscape</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-10-blockchain-crypto-landscapes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-10-blockchain-crypto-landscapes/</guid><description>Recording Click here to view the recording.
Description The School of Computer Science has invited Jeremy Clark, an associate professor at the Concordia Institute for Information Systems Engineering, to give a lecture on cryptocurrencies and blockchain technology!
The lecture will explore the world of decentralized finance and showcase the groundbreaking research taking place in this area! :scientist:
For more information, please visit: https://carleton.ca/scs/cu-events/ccss-presents-the-blockchain-and-cryptocurrency-landscape/</description></item><item><title>Project Showcase</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-05-project-showcase/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-05-project-showcase/</guid><description>Description SCESoc and the CCSS are collaborating this semester to bring you an epic Project Showcase Night!
Got any side projects or class projects you&amp;rsquo;re super stoked about sharing? Maybe you&amp;rsquo;ve been developing a game or a website that you really want to show off.
Join us all on March 5th to present your projects (finished or not!) to your peers! Sign up here if you want to showcase your project: https://forms.</description></item><item><title>A Chat With Ross Video</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-02-a-chat-with-ross-video/</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-03-02-a-chat-with-ross-video/</guid><description>Description Shawn Snider, current VP Production Workflow and Cloud Services at Ross Video and Carleton University graduate, will be sharing his experience in the workforce. He will discuss why he made the decision to join Ross, his career progression, and how his education and continuous learning has helped him along the way! As always, there will be a Q&amp;amp;A to follow to answer all your questions!</description></item><item><title>Vulnerabilities in Web Apps</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-17-vulnerabilities-in-web-apps/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-17-vulnerabilities-in-web-apps/</guid><description>Description On Wednesday, February 17, Robert Babaev gave a tech talk during dev club about web application security! Students learned how they could keep their website safe from SQL vulnerabilities, sensitive data exposure, and cross-site scripting.
To view a copy of the slides, click here!</description></item><item><title>Rustlang Workshop</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-10-rustlang-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-02-10-rustlang-workshop/</guid><description>Description Have you wanted to learn the Rust language? The time is now! Come out to this week&amp;rsquo;s dev club to learn it from your local Rustacean, @Forest for the trees. You&amp;rsquo;ll learn the language basics, what the language&amp;rsquo;s use cases are, and how you can keep learning it on your own!</description></item><item><title>Database Paradigms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-27-database-paradigms/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-27-database-paradigms/</guid><description>Description We&amp;rsquo;re back with more more bi-weekly Tech Talks on Wednesdays during Dev Club! This week we&amp;rsquo;re talking database paradigms&amp;ndash; Matthew, Director of Finance/Academics, will be going over several new and old types of database engines including Relational, NoSQL, Graph databases, and more!
The presentation will cover the pros, cons, and use cases for each variety of database and will expand off the material covered in COMP 3005 and COMP 2406.</description></item><item><title>Finding your First Internship</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-16-finding-internships/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-16-finding-internships/</guid><description>Description Trying to find your first internship during this pandemic and feel like giving up? Don’t throw in the towel just yet! On Saturday, January 16th from 12 - 1 PM on our Discord, the CCSS is going to give you a quick crash course on how to land your first CS gig, even if you’re in your first year. The presentation slides can be viewed here!</description></item><item><title>Figma Workshop</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-13-figma-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2021-01-13-figma-workshop/</guid><description>Description Our very own Omar Flores is giving a Tech Talk introducing Figma on Wednesday, January 13th from 6-8 PM on Microsoft Teams! Figma is currently the most used design tool in tech from vector graphics and illustrations to buttons and design systems to prototypes. Come learn the basics of this incredible tool and how to begin building prototypes!
Omar is a third year Carleton CS student who&amp;rsquo;s worked as a software developer intern at Google, RBC and Deloitte :computer: He&amp;rsquo;s passionate about design and excited to show us the ropes on Wednesday so don&amp;rsquo;t miss out!</description></item><item><title>Building a Hello World Web App</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-12-02-building-a-hello-world-web-app/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-12-02-building-a-hello-world-web-app/</guid><description>Description Don&amp;rsquo;t miss our last Tech Talk of the Fall term!
Bundlers, Babel, polyfills, Node.js, NPM, Terser, TypeScript, JavaScript module formats, sourcemaps, and more. Learn about the different tools used in the modern web development ecosystem and how to string them all together in this presentation from Carleton Alumni Bailey D&amp;rsquo;Amour! This presentation should give you the knowledge of how to setup and structure your web projects for a smooth coding and debugging experience.</description></item><item><title>Mini Hack: Building Native Applications</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-11-29-mini-hack-building-native-applications/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-11-29-mini-hack-building-native-applications/</guid><description>Description Are you a first-year student looking to expand your technical knowledge and learn to build native applications? CCSS First Year Rep, Milo, will be hosting the first themed mini hackathon of the year on November 29 from 11 - 1 pm EST! Students will learn how to write an application that opens a window and displays graphics on the screen using a graphical user interface toolkit. Don&amp;rsquo;t worry if you have no prior experience - we&amp;rsquo;ll be teaching you from scratch and introducing you to the tools!</description></item><item><title>Guide to the Game Dev Industry</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-11-04-guide-to-the-game-dev-industry/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-11-04-guide-to-the-game-dev-industry/</guid><description>Description Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a gamer or an aspiring game developer, you don&amp;rsquo;t want to miss our latest Dev Club Tech Talk - Guide to the Game Development Industry by Ian Harrison, Software Developer at Electronic Arts and CU Alumni. Come catch Ian talking about what it&amp;rsquo;s like to work in the industry, what it takes to support a live mobile title, the technologies used and more on Wednesday, November 4th at 6 - 8 PM!</description></item><item><title>A Beginner's Guide to Linux</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-10-14-beginners-guide-to-linux/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-10-14-beginners-guide-to-linux/</guid><description>Description Tech Talk Announcement! ⁣ ⁣ Confused by this whole Linux thing? Learn how to use Linux, and why you should know how to use it in the first place!⁣ This talk will cover a live installation, beginner usage, and how knowing Linux can benefit your degree and future career.⁣ ⁣ Join us during Dev Club next Wednesday, Oct. 14th starting at 6pm to watch. Hope to see you there!</description></item><item><title>Transfer Entropy, Influence, Measurement, &amp; Network Analysis</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-09-30-dave-tech-talk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-09-30-dave-tech-talk/</guid><description>Description Coming up next for the CCSS Dev Club is a tech talk from our very own Dr. Dave McKenney on Wednesday September 30th from 6 to 8 PM on our CCSS Discord! Dave&amp;rsquo;s been teaching COMP 1405, 1406 and 2406 and is also running his own Carleton Web Dev Club. Come listen to Dave talk about his thesis and work on transfer entropy, influence measurement and network analysis and be sure to bring lots of questions!</description></item><item><title>Week of Awesome: Intro to Hacking</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-09-16-intro-to-hacking/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2020-2021/academic/2020-09-16-intro-to-hacking/</guid><description>Description For this year&amp;rsquo;s Week of Awesome Tech Talk, we&amp;rsquo;ve enlisted the help Forest, a beloved CCSS veteran, to give a talk on the information security industry. He&amp;rsquo;ll be exploring the mindset behind solving problems in different domains such as cryptography, steganography, and web, leaving you with some resources at the end on how to learn more for yourself!
This talk will be hosted on Wednesday, September 16 at 2:00 PM EDT, here on the CCSS Discord server.</description></item><item><title>Python Workshop: What To Do With COMP 1405</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2020-02-05-python-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2020-02-05-python-workshop/</guid><description>Description Learn how to brainstorm, plan, and develop fun and interesting personal projects with just the content taught in COMP1405.
In this workshop we&amp;rsquo;ll bring project ideas, talk about how we came up with them, then help everyone brainstorm their own ideas. Finally, we&amp;rsquo;ll go through what&amp;rsquo;s involved in starting one of these projects and develop one ourselves</description></item><item><title>Code Editor Workshop</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2020-01-15-code-editor-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2020-01-15-code-editor-workshop/</guid><description>Description With so many code editors out there, it can be very hard to choose which is best for the job. At this workshop, we will be going over numerous code editors/IDE&amp;rsquo;s and the cool features that each provide! This would include extensions, linters, and much, much more!</description></item><item><title>React Workshop</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2019-10-09-react-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2019-10-09-react-workshop/</guid><description>Description React is a JavaScript library for building user interfaces. It is maintained by Facebook and can be used as a base in the development of single-page or mobile applications. The workshop will cover topics such as the Virtual DOM, class &amp;amp; functional components, React Hooks and more!</description></item><item><title>Linux Workshop</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2019-10-02-linux-workshop/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2019-10-02-linux-workshop/</guid><description>Description An introduction into using Linux and how to troubleshoot your problems. We will be going over basic Linux utilization and troubleshooting with hands-on activities inside a virtual machine. Bringing your laptop is strongly recommended so you can participate in the activities.</description></item><item><title>Week of Awesome: Demystifying Machine Learning (Tech Talk)</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2019-09-11-machine-learning-talk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/events/2019-2020/academic/2019-09-11-machine-learning-talk/</guid><description>Description Demystifying Machine Learning is a beginner-focused tech talk introducing students to AI and Machine Learning.</description></item></channel></rss>