<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CCSS Puzzle Quest</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2022-2023/2022-06-20-ccss-summer-dev-projects-introduction-copy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2022-2023/2022-06-20-ccss-summer-dev-projects-introduction-copy/</guid><description>Hello! Welcome to the CCSS Puzzle Quest! Throughout the next hour and a half, you&amp;rsquo;ll be working on 25 challenges, in 5 different categories.
Submitting To submit each challenge, fill out this Google Form for each question.
Chose only the challenge you&amp;rsquo;re submitting! Leaderboard You can check out the leaderboard on this document:
https://hackmd.io/zp90MdBaT3-WzdXcM-8bMw?view
Challenges Treasure Hunt For all of these challenges, take a selfie with your team at these locations!</description></item><item><title>CCSS Summer Dev Projects</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2022-2023/2022-06-20-ccss-summer-dev-projects-introduction/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2022-2023/2022-06-20-ccss-summer-dev-projects-introduction/</guid><description>CCSS Summer Dev Projects This summer, the CCSS is running several &amp;ldquo;summer dev projects&amp;rdquo;. This gives Carleton students several projects to contribute to over the summer, which are designed to help other students. You can read more about the projects on this Notion document.
This blog post will introduce some of the students behind these projects. Any student can participate, and many are in different years of university. There are also many different skill sets in use, with development to the frontend of websites, backend web servers, and even some other tooling in the middle.</description></item><item><title>A Case For Open Source</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-03-10-a-case-for-open-source/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-03-10-a-case-for-open-source/</guid><description>Open source software development is a methodology that has grown significantly in the last few years. Although the open source mindset has been around since the early days of operating system development, it has only become mainstream in the last decade due to advances in how we communicate and share code. Many companies are shifting towards tech stacks that are in part or are entirely open source. Open source developers are able to make careers off their work through sponsorship.</description></item><item><title>Sneak Peak</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-03-09-sneak-peak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-03-09-sneak-peak/</guid><description>I’m in the game development stream and I have a secret - I don’t play games! When I was in my first game design class, I noticed the disappointment of my classmates when they realized the first assignment was a written piece where we had to analyze any game we enjoyed. The professor brought up our obvious disappointment and explained that often kids go into game development since they just like playing games and only want to build them.</description></item><item><title>Studying From Home</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-01-28-studying-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-01-28-studying-from-home/</guid><description>Studying from home has its pros and cons. I made the decision to study abroad to get international exposure and experience the unique university life but due to the current situation, I have to accept the fact that I have to study online for one year, which has been the biggest con. I figured that pouting about it won’t work and that I just have to accept that fact and try and make the most of it so here is my experience so far with being an international online CS student.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Isaac Bragg Gardiner</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-01-12-meeting-issac-bragg-gardiner/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-01-12-meeting-issac-bragg-gardiner/</guid><description>With the dire situation in Ottawa and the amounting of cases, the city and quite frankly, anywhere, can get pretty lonely sometimes. Thankfully Computer Science students seem to hold their ground during the pandemic as our species seems to never poke our heads out of the safety and warmth of our rooms. However, as comparable as we are to the furry little groundhogs at Carleton, our lifestyle is still being affected more than meets the eye, especially in our classes.</description></item><item><title>Top 5 Amazing VSCode Extensions</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2020-11-26-top-five-vscode-extensions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2020-11-26-top-five-vscode-extensions/</guid><description>5. Rainbow CSV by mechatroner Rainbow CSV is a column highlighter to help people read CSV and TSV files. In addition, it provides information about a column on hover. With CSVLint, there is an automatic consistency check for CSV files. With the RBQL console, users can view the data in a colourful table format and run queries in an SQL-like language. From my experiences, Rainbow CSV helps me read and edit CSV files.</description></item></channel></rss>