<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Blog on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/</link><description>Recent content in Blog on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2020 23:11:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Undergraduate Research Opportunities for Computer Science Students</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2024-2025/2025-02-10-research-in-undergrad/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2024-2025/2025-02-10-research-in-undergrad/</guid><description>What is research? The goal of academic research is to add to the body of knowledge within a field. Generally speaking, research either aims to understand (e.g. “Are there biases in the outputs produced by large language models?) or to create (e.g. “Here is a new protocol for sending messages across the internet”). Depending on the specific field, this could involve running experiments or simulations, designing algorithms or processes, interviewing or observing participants in a study, and so on.</description></item><item><title>John's Journey through Students as Partners Program</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2023-2024/2023-12-22-sapp-journey/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2023-2024/2023-12-22-sapp-journey/</guid><description>Hello! My name is John, and I&amp;rsquo;m going to be chatting a little about my experience with the Students as Partners Program.
What is SaPP? Students as Partners Program(SaPP for short) is a 1-2 term project, where you create/develop curriculum resources for a professor&amp;rsquo;s class. It can range from a website that shows how something is done to articles on what to focus on in a course. An example of something that could be but isn&amp;rsquo;t an SaPP project is DiscreteMath.</description></item><item><title>A Case For Open Source</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-03-10-a-case-for-open-source/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-03-10-a-case-for-open-source/</guid><description>Open source software development is a methodology that has grown significantly in the last few years. Although the open source mindset has been around since the early days of operating system development, it has only become mainstream in the last decade due to advances in how we communicate and share code. Many companies are shifting towards tech stacks that are in part or are entirely open source. Open source developers are able to make careers off their work through sponsorship.</description></item><item><title>Sneak Peak</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-03-09-sneak-peak/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-03-09-sneak-peak/</guid><description>I’m in the game development stream and I have a secret - I don’t play games! When I was in my first game design class, I noticed the disappointment of my classmates when they realized the first assignment was a written piece where we had to analyze any game we enjoyed. The professor brought up our obvious disappointment and explained that often kids go into game development since they just like playing games and only want to build them.</description></item><item><title>Studying From Home</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-01-28-studying-from-home/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-01-28-studying-from-home/</guid><description>Studying from home has its pros and cons. I made the decision to study abroad to get international exposure and experience the unique university life but due to the current situation, I have to accept the fact that I have to study online for one year, which has been the biggest con. I figured that pouting about it won’t work and that I just have to accept that fact and try and make the most of it so here is my experience so far with being an international online CS student.</description></item><item><title>Meeting Isaac Bragg Gardiner</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-01-12-meeting-issac-bragg-gardiner/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2021-01-12-meeting-issac-bragg-gardiner/</guid><description>With the dire situation in Ottawa and the amounting of cases, the city and quite frankly, anywhere, can get pretty lonely sometimes. Thankfully Computer Science students seem to hold their ground during the pandemic as our species seems to never poke our heads out of the safety and warmth of our rooms. However, as comparable as we are to the furry little groundhogs at Carleton, our lifestyle is still being affected more than meets the eye, especially in our classes.</description></item><item><title>Top 5 Amazing VSCode Extensions</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2020-11-26-top-five-vscode-extensions/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/blog/2020-2021/2020-11-26-top-five-vscode-extensions/</guid><description>5. Rainbow CSV by mechatroner Rainbow CSV is a column highlighter to help people read CSV and TSV files. In addition, it provides information about a column on hover. With CSVLint, there is an automatic consistency check for CSV files. With the RBQL console, users can view the data in a colourful table format and run queries in an SQL-like language. From my experiences, Rainbow CSV helps me read and edit CSV files.</description></item></channel></rss>