<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>announcement on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/categories/announcement/</link><description>Recent content in announcement on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/categories/announcement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Welcome to the Fall Term</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/fall-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/fall-2022/</guid><description>Welcome to the Fall Term! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to be back and are looking forward to a offering a wide variety of events and services this term.
CCSS Puzzle Quest Week of Awesome Volunteer Opportunities First Year Representative Nominations CCSS 2022-2023 Hoodies CCSS Dev Projects CCSS Office Hours CCSS Puzzle Quest Starting off this term, we are excited to be hosting our first ever CCSS Puzzle Quest! Try lock picking, complete an escape room, and find some landmarks around campus to get the highest score before the time is up!</description></item><item><title>Our new Logo</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/our-new-logo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/our-new-logo/</guid><description>With the beginning of the new academic year, we really thought it was finally time to give the CCSS a new coat of paint. After quite a lot of variation, we&amp;rsquo;re proud to present a symbol that we believe represents our program, community, and our mission as an organization.
Why we needed a new logo Although we loved our previous logo very dearly, there were some issues with its design.</description></item><item><title>CCSS General Elections 2022-2023</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2022-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2022-2023/</guid><description>The Board consists of the following six positions:
President Vice President Director of Finance Director of Academics Director of Social Director of Community Here is the breakdown of this year&amp;rsquo;s electoral period:
Nomination Period: February 28 - March 6 Campaigning Period: March 10 - March 20 Voting Period: March 21 - March 23 If you want to run for a CCSS Board of Directors position for the 2022-2023 academic year, please fill out the Nomination Form here.</description></item><item><title>CCSS Development Mentorship Program</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/ccss-development-mentorship-program/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/ccss-development-mentorship-program/</guid><description>Applications now open!
Have you been meaning to start developing your own projects but have no idea how to start or keep going? Or maybe you’ve already been dabbling on projects and want to share your experience and insight with programmers who are starting out? You can now apply to become a development mentor or mentee! Applications are open until end of day January 26th.
Mentor Application Mentee Application
What does a mentor do?</description></item></channel></rss>