<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Announcement on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/categories/announcement/</link><description>Recent content in Announcement on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/categories/announcement/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>CCSS General Election Platforms</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections-2026-2027/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections-2026-2027/</guid><description>The CCSS Elections for 2026-2027 have begun! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to announce that we have 16 candidates running for positions on the Board of Directors.</description></item><item><title>CCSS General Elections 2026-2027</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2026-2027/</link><pubDate>Mon, 02 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2026-2027/</guid><description>What is the CCSS Board of Directors? The Board of Directors is a group of elected students who work with Carleton&amp;rsquo;s School of Computer Science to organize events, services, and other activities for the benefit of the undergraduate computer science student body.
The board consists of the following seven positions:
President: The President is responsible for leading the ideation and planning of the year while acting as the figurehead of the organization and a liaison with the School of Computer Science.</description></item><item><title>CCSS General Elections 2025-2026</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2025-2026/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2025-2026/</guid><description>What is the CCSS Board of Directors? The Board of Directors is a group of elected students who work with Carleton&amp;rsquo;s School of Computer Science to organize events, services, and other activities for the benefit of the undergraduate computer science student body.
The board consists of the following seven positions:
President: The President is responsible for leading the ideation and planning of the year while acting as the figurehead of the organization and a liaison with the School of Computer Science.</description></item><item><title>Carleton Computer Science Society Levy Referendum</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/carleton-computer-science-society-levy-referendum/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/carleton-computer-science-society-levy-referendum/</guid><description>Over the past decade, Carleton’s Computer Science program has grown rapidly and our student population has tripled. However, funding for the initiatives that enhance your university experience, especially those tailored for computer science students, has not kept pace.
Today, the Carleton Computer Science Society (CCSS) only receives $3,000 in consistent funding each year. With such limited financial support, it’s becoming increasingly difficult to maintain our services, especially large-scale events like hackathons and company networking nights that draw hundreds of participants.</description></item><item><title>Introducing The Computer Science Question Repository</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/computer-science-question-repository/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/computer-science-question-repository/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;ve taken COMP 2804 in the previous few years, then you&amp;rsquo;re most likely familliar with the website &amp;ldquo;DiscreteMath.ca&amp;rdquo;.
DiscreteMath.ca was built and maintained by CCSS executives and volunteers over the years and we&amp;rsquo;re excited to welcome you to the latest version of the site.
The Carleton Computer Science Question Repository is an upgraded version of DiscreteMath.ca built with the idea of eventually supporting more than just COMP 2804 and designed to improve the experience of contributing to the site.</description></item><item><title>CCSS General Elections 2024-2025</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2024-2025/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2024-2025/</guid><description>What is the CCSS Board of Directors? The Board of Directors is a group of elected students who work with Carleton&amp;rsquo;s School of Computer Science to organize events, services, and other activities for the benefit of the undergraduate computer science student body.
The board consists of the following seven positions:
President: The President is responsible for leading the ideation and planning of the year while acting as the figurehead of the organization and a liaison with the School of Computer Science.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Fall Term</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/fall-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/fall-2023/</guid><description>Welcome to the Fall Term! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to be back and are looking forward to a offering a wide variety of events and services this term.
CCSS Puzzle Quest Week of Awesome Hack the Tunnels Volunteer Opportunities First Year Representative Nominations CCSS 2023-2024 Hoodies Orientation 2023 If you&amp;rsquo;re interested in checking out the 2023 orientation slides, click here.
CCSS Puzzle Quest Starting off this term, we are excited to be hosting CCSS Puzzle Quest as part of SciFrosh!</description></item><item><title>CCSS General Elections 2023-2024</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2023-2024/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2023-2024/</guid><description>What is the CCSS Board of Directors? The board of directors is a group of elected students who work with Carleton&amp;rsquo;s School of Computer Science to organize and run events, services, and other activities for the benefit of the undergraduate computer science student body.
The board consists of the following six positions:
President: Is responsible for leading the ideation and planning of the year while acting as the figurehead of the organization and a liaison between students and the School of Computer Science.</description></item><item><title>Winter Hoodie Sale</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/winter-hoodies-2022-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/winter-hoodies-2022-2023/</guid><description>View this post on Instagram A post shared by CCSS (@carletoncss)
Hoodies will be sold on our Shopify store page until January 31th @ Midnight! We will not be selling hoodies at the CCSS lounge after this as we will be doing one bulk order based on the number of orders we receive.</description></item><item><title>CCSS Hoodies 2022-2023</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/hoodies-2022-2023/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/hoodies-2022-2023/</guid><description>Hoodies will be sold on our Shopify store page until September 30th @ Midnight! We will not be selling hoodies at the CCSS lounge after this as we will be doing one bulk order based on the number of orders we receive.</description></item><item><title>Welcome to the Fall Term</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/fall-2022/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Sep 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/fall-2022/</guid><description>Welcome to the Fall Term! We&amp;rsquo;re excited to be back and are looking forward to a offering a wide variety of events and services this term.
CCSS Puzzle Quest Week of Awesome Volunteer Opportunities First Year Representative Nominations CCSS 2022-2023 Hoodies CCSS Dev Projects CCSS Office Hours CCSS Puzzle Quest Starting off this term, we are excited to be hosting our first ever CCSS Puzzle Quest! Try lock picking, complete an escape room, and find some landmarks around campus to get the highest score before the time is up!</description></item><item><title>Our new Logo</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/our-new-logo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/our-new-logo/</guid><description>With the beginning of the new academic year, we really thought it was finally time to give the CCSS a new coat of paint. After quite a lot of variation, we&amp;rsquo;re proud to present a symbol that we believe represents our program, community, and our mission as an organization.
Why we needed a new logo Although we loved our previous logo very dearly, there were some issues with its design.</description></item><item><title>CCSS General Elections 2022-2023</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2022-2023/</link><pubDate>Mon, 14 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/general-elections-2022-2023/</guid><description>The Board consists of the following six positions:
President Vice President Director of Finance Director of Academics Director of Social Director of Community Here is the breakdown of this year&amp;rsquo;s electoral period:
Nomination Period: February 28 - March 6 Campaigning Period: March 10 - March 20 Voting Period: March 21 - March 23 If you want to run for a CCSS Board of Directors position for the 2022-2023 academic year, please fill out the Nomination Form here.</description></item><item><title>CCSS Development Mentorship Program</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/ccss-development-mentorship-program/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/news/ccss-development-mentorship-program/</guid><description>Applications now open!
Have you been meaning to start developing your own projects but have no idea how to start or keep going? Or maybe you’ve already been dabbling on projects and want to share your experience and insight with programmers who are starting out? You can now apply to become a development mentor or mentee! Applications are open until end of day January 26th.
Mentor Application Mentee Application</description></item></channel></rss>