<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elections on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/</link><description>Recent content in Elections on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Jacc's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/president/jacc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/president/jacc/</guid><description>Hey everyone 👋 I&amp;rsquo;m Jacc, your current Co-Director of Academics and former Director of Publications. I&amp;rsquo;m running for CCSS President, and here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to accomplish during my term:
1. Bigger Focus on Development Opportunities The problem: The CCSS hasn&amp;rsquo;t consistently planned initiatives that help students build development skills outside of coursework. We often give students the advice that they need personal projects to stand out, but don&amp;rsquo;t provide enough structured support to actually help them do that.</description></item><item><title>Aidan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/aidan/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/aidan/</guid><description>Hey! I&amp;rsquo;m Aidan and I&amp;rsquo;m starting in the new Bachelor of Cybersecurity program.
As a first year representative my primary goal will be to continue building the CCSS community by creating as many opportunities as possible for other first year students to engage with the society and make connections with their peers and upper year students alike. I&amp;rsquo;m especially interested in ensuring that the CCSS is able to host many events where members can learn, practice, and demonstrate programming and other technical skills.</description></item><item><title>Alvin's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/alvin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/alvin/</guid><description>First year CS may feel like being thrown into the deep end for a lot a people. You have assignments piling up like Jenga - COMP1405, MATH 1007, COMP1805, etc. and yet you are expected to maintain a social life? Yeah, but no thank you.
If I&amp;rsquo;m a first-year representative, I want the entire experience to be less about &amp;ldquo;why is this happening to me?&amp;rdquo; and more like, &amp;ldquo;y&amp;rsquo;know what&amp;hellip; It&amp;rsquo;s not too bad&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo;</description></item><item><title>Durvish's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/durvish/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/durvish/</guid><description>✨ Quick Synopsis (aka summary of why you should vote for me): 🎤 Q&amp;amp;A with seniors → real advice, not Google answers.
🎮 Fun events → game nights, coding jams, study squads.
💼 Co-op/internships → less stress, more confidence.
🚀 Hackathons &amp;amp; Recruiters → skills, networks, and building memories.
❤️ A first-year experience that’s not just about surviving but thriving.
Full Platform: If elected as First-Year Representative, my priority would be to make sure that every first-year student feels heard, supported, and connected within the Computer Science community.</description></item><item><title>Jack's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/jack/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/jack/</guid><description>🙋 Who am I? Hey! I’m Jack, a first-year Computer Science student in the Cybersecurity stream running to be your representative. To be brief, my goal is to make our first year more connected by creating opportunities to meet new people, build friendships, and support each other academically. I want to foster a community where students feel included, engaged, and able to grow together.
Below are some highlights from my platform.</description></item><item><title>Karthi's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/karthi/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/karthi/</guid><description>Why I’m Running 🏃💨: First year is exciting… and slightly terrifying. Five classes, 300-page lecture slides, and trying to make friends? Yeah, it’s chaos. I don’t want anyone going through this alone. Your Voice Matters 🎤: If there’s one thing I care about besides a 12.0 GPA , it’s making sure you’re heard. Heavy workloads? Confusing assignments? Or just praying for a “For Dummies” version of the course content—I got you.</description></item><item><title>Krisha's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/krisha/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/krisha/</guid><description>Hey everyone!! If I am elected, I promise to give it my all to debug the first-year issues, because problems deserve solutions, not crashes (we get enough of those writing code anyways). My name is Krisha and I’m super excited to be running for your First-Year Representative for the Carleton Computer Science Society!
ACADEMIC SUPPORT AND FUTURE EVENTS: Even within our first month, tests and assignments are already piling up, which can feel really overwhelming.</description></item><item><title>Megh's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/megh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/megh/</guid><description>Hey everyone! My name is Megh, and I&amp;rsquo;m a first year Computer Science Honours student. Starting university will be exciting as well as can be overwhelming, so I want to help make the first year fun and supportive for new students.
So, here&amp;rsquo;s what I plan to do if I am elected as a First Year Representative:
Study Sessions: I&amp;rsquo;ll organize study sessions before midterms and final exams, so we can study in a group and discuss any problems and also will have study sessions with our peers so that we can connect with peers, learn some new things and share any tips.</description></item><item><title>Omar's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/omar/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/omar/</guid><description>Hey everyone! My name is Omar, and I&amp;rsquo;m in the Bachelor of Cybersecurity. I&amp;rsquo;m super excited to run to be one of your First Year Representatives.
The transition from high school to university is one that is equal parts abrupt, hard and exciting. My goal is to smooth out that transition as best as I possibly could for all of us.
As your First Year Rep., here&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;ll do for you:</description></item><item><title>Rudraksh's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/rudraksh/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/rudraksh/</guid><description>Hi everyone, I am Rudraksh Sharma, a fellow first year at Carleton University. I am in the Bachelors in Comp Sci Program with an AI/ML Stream and am running for First Year Computer Science Rep!!
Now, I won’t ask for your votes (well not in the way everyone else does it), but rather, I just want some of your valuable time. Time, to read this and understand the vision I hold for our First Year memories that are yet to be made.</description></item><item><title>Simak's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/simak/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/simak/</guid><description>About Me My name is Simak Safwan, and I’m running to be your CCSS First-Year Representative. I live in Ottawa and graduated from high school here.
Why You Should Vote For Me I bring leadership experience from high school as a Link Crew Leader, Vice-President of the MEDLIFE Club, and Yearbook Design Lead, as well as through involvement with other student groups where I represented my peers.
I will ensure that first-year voices are heard in the CCSS and that your ideas, concerns, and interests are brought forward to the governing body of the society.</description></item><item><title>Sofia's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/sofia/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/sofia/</guid><description>Introduction Hey everyone!!! I’m Sofia, and I’m a first-year student here at Carleton! I’m studying computer science, stream: Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning. AI to me is really interesting and I would love to learn more about it. As you may all know, AI might have unpleasant consequences on our future, however, I believe that it has the power to change the world for the better and I would like to be part of that change!</description></item><item><title>Stephen's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/stephen/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2025-2026/stephen/</guid><description>Hi, I’m Stephen.
As your representative, I will help organize events featuring math-based coding challenges. These will be similar to Math Olympiad questions but less difficult, making them very interesting for anyone who enjoys coding and mathematics.
Introducing you to Coding Challenges If you are familiar with LeetCode, you can expect questions in a similar style. I also draw inspiration from platforms like Codeforces and AtCoder, which tend to be more math-heavy.</description></item><item><title>Adrian's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/finance/adrian/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/finance/adrian/</guid><description>Hello everyone! My name is Adrian Ponce. I’m a Computer Science Software Engineering student entering my third year while minoring in Finance. My vision as your Director of Finance is built on three pillars:
1. 📈Strengthening our society’s financial stability: A critical window to strengthen our society’s financial future relies on Ontario’s historic $6.4 billion investment in the postsecondary sector, which is stabilizing university budgets and expanding high-demand programs like computer science.</description></item><item><title>Afaq's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/industry/afaq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/industry/afaq/</guid><description>REASONS to VOTE AFAQ VIRK as Director of Industry Initiatives 🔥🔥🔥 I am industrious 🤑 (2 years of internship experience + 5 years managing a business) I understand both sides of the table: what employers expect, and what students actually need. I’ve operated in professional environments and built things from scratch on my own time.
I will help you get a j*b 💼 (i’ll go so far as to mock interview or tutor you personally, just ask me, I’ve done it before).</description></item><item><title>Alvin's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/alvin/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/alvin/</guid><description>You&amp;rsquo;re trying to avoid falling behind while balancing deadlines and lectures.
Better support is what you need: easily accessible materials, productive study sessions, and someone who pays attention to courses.
I&amp;rsquo;ve assisted in running review sessions and volunteered with CCSS, so I&amp;rsquo;ve seen what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t.
What’s not working for you Rather than working with others, you tend to grind alone. Some classes seem more difficult than they actually are because there isn&amp;rsquo;t organized support for them.</description></item><item><title>Durvish's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/industry/durvish/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/industry/durvish/</guid><description>“From lecture halls to LinkedIn calls, let’s break down walls and land real roles.” - DJ
I’m running for Director of Industry Initiatives because I believe opportunity shouldn’t be accidental, it should be intentional, organized, and accessible to every student. I don’t want to wait for the right moment, I want to create it!
Too often, students (sometimes including myself) feel like breaking into tech is a black box. You apply.</description></item><item><title>Harshita's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/content-creation/harshita/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/content-creation/harshita/</guid><description>Ever had a conversation with a prof, classmate, or an upper-year student and walked away thinking &amp;ldquo;wow, I would&amp;rsquo;ve never known that if they hadn&amp;rsquo;t told me&amp;rdquo;? I definitely have.🙋‍♀️
Maybe it was job search advice that actually helped. Shared struggles in a course that made you feel less alone (looking at you Discrete Structures). A cool CS opportunity you didn&amp;rsquo;t even know existed. All the stuff that spreads through word of mouth meaning most of us never hear it.</description></item><item><title>Karthi's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/content-creation/karthi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/content-creation/karthi/</guid><description>What&amp;rsquo;s up!! Hello guys, My name is Karthi Kanthavel and I am currently the First Year Representative who runs a lot of the CCSS Instagram Reels (yes… the ones you actually watched).
I genuinely enjoy making fun, relatable content that gets students to pay attention instead of scrolling past.
I’m the type of person who likes to plan things properly, stay involved, and actually listen to students.
My goal is simple: make CCSS feel more alive, visible, and student-focused.</description></item><item><title>Kimia's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/operations/kimia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/operations/kimia/</guid><description>Hello everyone!
My name is Kimia, your current Director of Operations and I am running in hopes of being re-elected as your Director of Operations for the upcoming 2026-2027 academic year. I would be honoured to continue in this role to help further your experience here at Carleton University and with the society while also simultaneously continuing to support the behind-the-scenes here at the Carleton Computer Science Society.
During my time here, I have volunteered with the CCSS at numerous events and also continuously attended meetings and contributed to various discussions and initiatives.</description></item><item><title>Michael's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/finance/michael/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/finance/michael/</guid><description>Hey everyone! My name&amp;rsquo;s Michael and I&amp;rsquo;m running to be your next Director of Finance.
With this year&amp;rsquo;s introduction of the levy, we over budget for new costs like insurance. This leaves us with a surplus of funds to act as a buffer that we can maintain year over year, helping to ensure the long term stability of the society. With this year&amp;rsquo;s costs in mind, going forward, we can allocate more to initiatives that benefit each and every one of you.</description></item><item><title>Ming's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/ming/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/ming/</guid><description>WHY I’M RUNNING
Computer Science isn’t just challenging anymore — it’s hell and uncertain.
Layoffs, rising hiring standards, and rapid changes in technology have made one thing clear: working hard is no longer enough if we don’t know what actually matters.
Many students are constantly busy: assignments, side projects, interview prep, but still unsure whether they are building the right skills for co-op and beyond.
I am running to strengthen the connection between academics and career preparation.</description></item><item><title>Nolan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/finance/nolan/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/finance/nolan/</guid><description>Hello CCSS! My name is Nolan and I will be running for the Director of Finance for the 2026-27 school year. This year I will be going into my third year of CS with a minor in business. I would like to connect my knowledge of Business and Computer Science to help the CCSS raise and manage money. I plan on working closely with my fellow board members to bring more funding to the CCSS to create more events and opportunities for you!</description></item><item><title>Omar's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/finance/omar/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/finance/omar/</guid><description>Hello!👋 My name is Omar, and I am running for your vote for the position of Director of Finance.
Let me start by properly introducing myself, I’m a first year Cybersecurity student with long-standing passions for both technology and finance. My free time consists of me working on my homelab or playing video games with my friends. I’ve started volunteering with the CCSS in the lounge during the Fall of 2025.</description></item><item><title>Rieley's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/rieley/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/rieley/</guid><description>https://rieley.ca/platform
Hi everyone! I&amp;rsquo;m Rieley, a 4th year Computer Science student here at Carleton. I have been a TA for many courses including COMP1805 and COMP1405. I have also been the President of the Carleton Music Club for almost a year now. It would be no overstatement to say that I am well versed in organizing and realizing large-scale student initiatives.
Having worked both with instructors and directly with students, I understand something important:</description></item><item><title>Rudraksh's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/social/rudraksh/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/social/rudraksh/</guid><description>Hi Everyone!!! I’m Rudraksh Sharma, and I am excited to announce that I will be running for the Director of Social this sem!!!
I’m running to be Director of Social for the Carleton Computer Science Society because Computer Science should be more than assignments, labs, and debugging at 2AM. Yes, we grind. Yes, we lock in. But we also deserve a community that’s loud, welcoming, and actually fun to be part of.</description></item><item><title>Sarah's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/sarah/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/sarah/</guid><description>Hi everyone! I&amp;rsquo;m Sarah and I&amp;rsquo;m currently going into my second year of computer science in the cyber security stream.
I want to run as Director of Academics at the Carleton Computer Science Society. I&amp;rsquo;ve always been really passionate about creating an environment for my fellow peers where they feel supported, safe and empowered to succeed. Throughout my time in Carleton as a computer science student, I understand that right academic support is really important to succeed.</description></item><item><title>Sofia's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/sofia/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2026-2027/academics/sofia/</guid><description>Hey everyone!! I’m Sofia, and I’m running for Director of Academics because I genuinely care about making Computer Science more accessible, more supportive, and less overwhelming!
To be honest, CS is a lot. We all know it. Confusing assignments, late night debugging, unsure of how to study, andddd imposter syndrome… feeling like you’re behind even when you’re trying your best&amp;hellip; I know. It’s not easy, but I’m here to make sure YOU can easily access useful resources that will help you thrive!</description></item><item><title>Amanjot's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/social/amanjot/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/social/amanjot/</guid><description>Who Am I? 👤 Hi👋, my name is Amanjot, and I’m excited to run for Director of Social for the 2025-2026 CCSS Board of Directors! As someone who loves socializing and meeting new people, I believe that a strong sense of community makes the university experience more enjoyable and fulfilling. My previous leadership experience has given me the skills to plan events, bring people together, and create an inclusive space where everyone feels welcome.</description></item><item><title>Cameron's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/finance/cameron/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/finance/cameron/</guid><description>Hey everyone! I’m Cameron, and I’m running to be your Director of Finance for the 2024-2025 term. With the introduction of a new levy and the continued growth of our society, it’s more important than ever that we have solid financial management and strategic planning in place. I want to make sure your contributions are used fairly, and that computer science students can be proud to be a part of the CCSS.</description></item><item><title>Eros's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/industry/eros/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/industry/eros/</guid><description>Hello everyone, my name is Eros and I&amp;rsquo;m looking to be your 2025-2026 Director of Industry Initiatives. With our new student levy in place for the upcoming term we as a society are ready to take things to the next level.
Why should you vote for me? Well let me share with you what I want to accomplish as the Director of Industry Initiatives.
Laying the foundation for the future As Industry Initiatives Director, I will lay the foundation for long-term success by creating essential resources that future directors can build upon.</description></item><item><title>Jacc's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/academics/jacc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/academics/jacc/</guid><description>Hey everyone! My name is Aditya but you probably know me as Jacc. I’ve been involved as a volunteer with the CCSS throughout my time at Carleton, and I would like to continue next year as your Director of Academics!
Here are some of the highlights from my platform. If you would like to read my full campaign platform checkout my notion page!
Feel free to also click on any of the following points for more details.</description></item><item><title>Kimia's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/operations/kimia/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/operations/kimia/</guid><description>Hello! My name is Kimia and I am running in the CCSS General Election for the position of Director of Operations. I have frequently volunteered with the CCSS over the past few months and would be delighted to continue to do so and to have a greater impact and role in the society in order to further continue the efforts the CCSS puts to help represent all undergraduate computer science students.</description></item><item><title>Landon's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/publications/landon/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/publications/landon/</guid><description>New and Improved Resources: In my opinion, the website has room for additional resources for:
How to study for and where to find study material for courses that are often challenging. Often, in some of the harder second-year courses students may feel a little stuck. Instead of waiting for study session events to run on their specific course, this would be a permanent resource to help them get back on track.</description></item><item><title>Nandita's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/academics/nandita/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/academics/nandita/</guid><description>As a computer science student, I know how challenging and rewarding our courses can be. If elected as Director of Academics, I’ll work to make learning more accessible, engaging, and supportive for everyone.
I plan to:
Expand peer tutoring and study groups. Organize talks with industry professionals and researchers. Host coding competitions, hackathons, and workshops. My goal is to help students succeed by providing the right resources and opportunities. Let’s make academics fun and enjoyable together!</description></item><item><title>Nguyen's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/academics/nguyen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/academics/nguyen/</guid><description>Hi there! My name is Nguyen, and I&amp;rsquo;m a 4th-year CS student. Over the past two years, as a former teaching assistant I&amp;rsquo;ve had the privilege of helping host numerous academic events with the CCSS. My goal is simple: to provide you with the tools, resources, and support you need to succeed in your studies.
If elected, here&amp;rsquo;s what I plan to accomplish:
✏️ Expanding Publicly Available Academic Resources Having worked on the Carleton Computer Science Question Repository (and discretemath.</description></item><item><title>Nolan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/academics/nolan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/academics/nolan/</guid><description>Why I Want to Run
Hey, Carleton CS crew! 👋 I’m Nolan, a first-year CS student running for Director of Academics. New to coding, I get how tough this program is—late nights, steep curves. I want to make YOUR academic journey smoother with practical support starting Fall 2025. Inspired by CCSS events (like “Master Leetcode Challenges” and “DevOps with Ciena”), I’ll bring fresh crash courses and resources to boost our success.</description></item><item><title>Riley's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/social/riley/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/social/riley/</guid><description>Hey everyone! My name is Riley Lutz, and I’m excited to announce my candidacy for Director of Social for the 2025-2026 academic year.
I know that social interaction plays a vital role in our academic success and well-being. Whether it’s collaborating on that one vexing group project, networking for our career, or just doing a bit of trolling in the CCSS lounge, staying connected with peers is part of what makes our CS journey worth experiencing.</description></item><item><title>Veronica's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/president/veronica/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2025-2026/president/veronica/</guid><description>Hello everyone! I’m Veronica, the current president and previous first-year representative, and I am running with hopes of being re-elected as CCSS president for the coming year!
If I am re-elected, the following is what I would hope to accomplish during my term:
Ensuring Proper Use of Levy Funds Throughout the past couple of years, we have been vouching for the establishment of a levy fee of $2.50/term for full-time students - in hopes of maintaining the operational baseline that the CCSS maintains.</description></item><item><title>Afaq's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/afaq/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/afaq/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on all sides of education - as a computer science tutor, student, and school board trustee representing 27000 peers in Eastern Ontario. I&amp;rsquo;ve always had a strong focus on making CS education more accessible, extensive, and enjoyable!
As a first year rep, I&amp;rsquo;d hope to take advantage of my connections in the field to expand the current resources available to CCSS students - be it academic supports, or funds to create cool projects and plans to organize exciting events.</description></item><item><title>Alex's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/alex/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/alex/</guid><description>YOUR SUCCESS is my priority, and I mean it. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re looking to build your resume, network, make new friends, learn new skills, or even hit diamond in Valorant I am here to help you achieve your goals—okay, maybe not the Valorant one, but you get the idea!
LEARN INDUSTRY SKILLS: Want to get ahead of the game? Imagine having access to workshops on essential industry skills like GitHub, PowerShell, and more.</description></item><item><title>Chi's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/chi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/chi/</guid><description>Hello everyone! My name is Chi, and I’m excited to run for the position of First-Year Representative. I’m passionate not only about technology but also about the community that comes with it. I’m from Ottawa so if you’d like some food and restaurant suggestions, feel free to reach out and say hi! :)
As your first-year representative, here’s what I’d like to do for you:
1. Build a stronger community 🌱 Organizing weekly meetups where we can work on projects, discuss coursework, or hang out.</description></item><item><title>Jon-Luca's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/jon-luca/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/jon-luca/</guid><description>Hey! 👋 My name is Jon-Luca, and I’m a first-year Computer Science student in the Cybersecurity stream.
I’ll be hanging around the CCSS lounge often, so I’ll be easy to find if you want to chat! 😊
I know university can be pretty overwhelming, and reaching out to a representative might feel a bit daunting. That’s why I want to make myself as approachable as possible.
📢 Announcements &amp;amp; Visibility 📢 I plan to make CCSS announcements more accessible to everyone.</description></item><item><title>Maliha's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/maliha/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/maliha/</guid><description>As your first-year representative, I’ll ensure the voices of all first-year students feel heard while pushing to bridge gaps between all computer science students to foster a supportive, tight-knit community here at Carleton University.
While coding is commonly seen as a solitary task, I believe true strength lies in collaboration! First-year can be a very stressful and overwhelming experience for many, so I find it very important for CCSS to host various types of events to support students coming together and connecting with others.</description></item><item><title>Muhammad's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/muhammad/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/muhammad/</guid><description>The word limit is 500 I don&amp;rsquo;t need that let me keep it simple. If I was elected First-Year Representative best believe I&amp;rsquo;m going to make sure that first year student voices are heard by the board of the CCSS.
Being a first year student is crazy because more often than not we don&amp;rsquo;t really know what we&amp;rsquo;re getting ourselves into and if you are an international student like me we&amp;rsquo;re going in totally blind.</description></item><item><title>Randiv's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/randiv/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2024-2025/randiv/</guid><description>If I were elected as the First-Year Representative, my top priority would be to create a strong connection between first-year students and the CCSS. To guarantee that your voices are heard, I want to ensure all communication channels to the CCSS are clear and easily accessible. Staying informed about what the Society is hosting can sometimes feel overwhelming, so I focus on creating digestible updates, through social media, email, or even short video clips.</description></item><item><title>Aires' Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/industry/aires/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/industry/aires/</guid><description>Hello everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m Aires! As your first-year representative, I have ran several events related to networking, and I look forward to boost my impact as the Director of Industry initiatives. As the first Director of Industry Initiatives, I will be expanding on the events I planned this year and more.
📝Resume Review📝 This year, I organized the first resume roast at the beginning of the year where I invited a graduate student with FANG experience as well as two other reviewers with startup experience to come in as resume reviewers.</description></item><item><title>Benjamin's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/academics/ben/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/academics/ben/</guid><description>Hey everyone! My name is Ben, and I’m currently in 2nd year. Having already had 1 year of experience as your Director of Academics, I believe that I can help contribute to your academic success. Computer science is a hard program to get through, but I want to make YOUR life easier.
Here are some ideas I have to meet that goal:
Course-specific study groups
There are a lot of courses that could benefit from organized group study, and over the past year, I&amp;rsquo;ve helped run multiple study groups.</description></item><item><title>Camerons' Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/finance/cameron/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/finance/cameron/</guid><description>Hey everyone! My name is Cameron, and I&amp;rsquo;m excited to announce my candidacy for Director of Finance. With organization and financial efficiency at the front of my mind, I am eager to tackle the challenges and opportunities that lie ahead.
More Active Discussion on Spending Practices
I believe in transparency and accountability when it comes to spending practices. That&amp;rsquo;s why I&amp;rsquo;m committed to fostering more active discussions within our community about how we allocate our funds.</description></item><item><title>Dylan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/operations/dylan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/operations/dylan/</guid><description>I run for the CCSS BoD Operations position and write this manifesto with the same intent, keeping things “Short and Sweet”.
Keeping things brief and relevant: 0. About me - In Highschool and Pre-University College (outside of Canada), I have held positions on faculties, councils and clubs most notably President of Student Council, District Leader for the Red Crescent / Red Cross Association and Youth Camp Lead. I’ve actively competed in many STEM and Innovation based competitions with a side of Debating / Public speaking.</description></item><item><title>Jacc's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/social/jacc/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/social/jacc/</guid><description>Hello everyone! My name is Aditya but my friends call me Jacc. I’m an international student from India, currently in my first year of Computer Science with planned minors in Law and Film. Throughout this year, I have been a volunteer for several CCSS events. I am now running to be the Director of Social and hope to have a bigger impact on the Carleton CS community next year. Here are some of the ways I plan to achieve this goal:</description></item><item><title>John's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/operations/john/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/operations/john/</guid><description>Hello, my name is John. I’m your current Social Director and former First Year Rep.
In my two years at the CCSS, I&amp;rsquo;ve hosted many events for our community, If elected, I will improve the behind-the-scenes operations of the CCSS to ensure a continued delivery of high-quality events and services to all computer science students.
☁️ Hosting a Balanced Variety of Events We’ve had an imbalance of events in terms of the kinds of events.</description></item><item><title>Kelly's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/social/kelly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/social/kelly/</guid><description>Hey! I’m Kelly and I’m passionate about making university a memorable experience for everyone. Over the course of this school year, I’ve hosted various successful social events such as the Halloween Hang, Bob Ross Paint Night, and Mooney’s Bay Picnic. If elected as the Director of Social, I would want to introduce new social initiatives and plan even bigger fun events to connect students. Some of my goals for the CCSS in 2024-2025 are to:</description></item><item><title>Mary-Emma's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/publications/mary-emma/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/publications/mary-emma/</guid><description>Hey! I’m Mary-Emma, a third year Computer Science student with a minor in Professional Writing. I’ve volunteered at CCSS events in the past and have enjoyed attending their events since my first year at Carleton. Writing is a passion for me and I’m excited to combine my content creation experience from my Professional Writing minor with my love of computer science to help promote the CCSS.
As the Director of Publications, I would love to:</description></item><item><title>Rebecca's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/publications/rebecca/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/publications/rebecca/</guid><description>Hello! My name is Rebecca, and I’m a 3rd year(ish) CS student. You may know me from your classes, from the Cybersecurity club, from CCSS events, or from seeing me hang out and answer questions in the CCSS Discord. I believe the CCSS could greatly expand on the resources it is offering to students and I think I’d be a great person to help make that happen. Overall, my goal is to help create a permanent archive of searchable content that could be accessed by students asynchronously.</description></item><item><title>Richards's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/industry/richard/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/industry/richard/</guid><description>Hi!
I&amp;rsquo;m Richard Kim, a 4th year in Honours BCS. Some of you may know me as this year&amp;rsquo;s VP, the COMP 2406 TA (from previous years), or a peer mentor at SSSC!
So, why me as Director of Industry Initiatives?
Already On It: As the current Student Ambassador at Nokia, I&amp;rsquo;ve been coordinating with Nokia recruiters to set up a networking event this September. For those eyeing the Co-op job board, you&amp;rsquo;ll know Nokia is one of the biggest employers.</description></item><item><title>Ryan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/finance/ryan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/finance/ryan/</guid><description>Hey everyone! I’m Ryan, your current Director of Finance for the 2023-2024 school year!
In the past year, here is the impact I’ve achieved:
Additional funding through finding and researching different funds and their eligibility, enabling the CCSS to run large-scale events like Hack the Tunnels, and Increased projected cash spending from $3,000 to $9,000 this year, providing the resources to organize more events, resources, and services for you! If elected, here is what I plan to do:</description></item><item><title>Veronica's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/president/veronica/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2024-2025/president/veronica/</guid><description>Hello everyone, I’m Veronica and I am running in hopes of being voted in as the CCSS President for the coming year!
As your president, the following is what I would hope to accomplish during my term:
☕Coffee Chats
Within the past year - I have noticed that having connections with professors, and even upper years is incredibly helpful. However, as it stands, getting those connections going is quite difficult. This is why I strive to create a viable coffee chat system.</description></item><item><title>Aditya/Jacc's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/jacc/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/jacc/</guid><description>Hello everyone! My name is Aditya but my friends call me Jacc. I’m an international student from India and while I’m not currently in a stream, I’m considering minors in Law and Physics. You may know me as the owner of the “Carleton Class of ‘27” discord server. I have been running informational and social events for incoming first-year students over the summer. I have also been volunteering with the CCSS for the last few months to create a new resources section of the CCSS website.</description></item><item><title>Aidan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/aidan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/aidan/</guid><description>Hi, Class of 2027! My name is Aidan Nelson. If elected, I will advocate for 4 main initiatives:
1. Introductory Industry Events 💼 o More events like the industry mixer, for you to interact with potential employers and start building a professional network
o Presentations from older students in co-op, where you can address questions and concerns regarding the co-op process
o More presentations from people working in the computer science industry, for you to learn about networking and other aspects of the transition into a professional environment</description></item><item><title>Aires's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/aires/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/aires/</guid><description>Hello everyone, I&amp;rsquo;m Aires. As the former president of my high school coding club, I sure do love coding. I&amp;rsquo;m from Toronto, so I knew no one when I first came here, but I like to spontaneously greet random people, so if you have no one to say hi to, I&amp;rsquo;ll say hi to you.
💻Partnering With Other CS-Related Clubs💻 In most of our conversations with new people, the question of &amp;ldquo;&amp;ldquo;What stream are you in?</description></item><item><title>Jaime's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/jaime/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/jaime/</guid><description>Hello! My name is Jaime Sexton, and I’m a first year student in Computer Science (if you’re reading this, you probably are too). I’ve been interested in computer science for many years, and I would like to become more involved with the CCSS by being a first year representative!
💻 Representing all first years in Carleton Computer Science 💻 Representing first years is a very important task that I would take seriously.</description></item><item><title>Jensen's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/jensen/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/jensen/</guid><description>Hello, my name is Jensen and I am hoping to become your first year representative. I would like to improve the community, academics, and internship side at Carleton CS.
🛎️Always willing to Network and Collaborate🛎️ (with great Friendliness👍): You can always reach out to me if you would like to give me suggestions or collaborate with work. I am hoping to increase the activity of the Carleton community by hosting fun events where everyone could freely meetup.</description></item><item><title>Veronica's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/veronica/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2023-2024/veronica/</guid><description>Hello, fellow computer science first years! My name is Veronica Mordvinova, and I am very excited to run for the first-year representative position!
Before starting to talk about my plans for the upcoming year, and what I can do for you, let me tell you a little about myself, and the relevant experience that I have - that makes me the ideal candidate for the position
→ Experience representing the student body and their interests 2 years as secretary - student council</description></item><item><title>Abdulla's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/abdulla/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/abdulla/</guid><description>Hello my name is Abdulla (or Abood) and i&amp;rsquo;m a first year CS student just like all of you. I am an international student that came from Qatar and really looking forward to getting the school year started as the first year rep for the CCSS! I enjoy basketball, football, gaming and anime so dont hesitate to say hi to me if you ever see me around campus. As for why I should be elected for the position:</description></item><item><title>Chris' Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/chris/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/chris/</guid><description>Hi there! I’m Chris, and this fall I’m hoping to be elected as one of your First-Year Representatives! You’ll find some of the things I look forward to doing if I am elected listed in the points below. If you’d like to contact me, feel free to send me an email at christopherchallis@cmail.carleton.ca or send me a message on discord at CoffeeChris#9305.
📣 Represent all First-Years within the CCSS! If I were to be elected as a First Year Representative my top priority would be to listen to and represent all of the interests, ideas, questions and concerns coming from the first-year students in the CCSS.</description></item><item><title>Hassan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/hassan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/hassan/</guid><description>Hey, I&amp;rsquo;m Hassan Ali! Like all of you, I&amp;rsquo;m a first-year computer science student. After attending the CCSS Fall general meeting and a few of the other amazing events this week, I decided to run for First Year Representative as I believe that I could have a real impact on the Carleton Computer Science Society.
At the Fall Meeting, there were a few issues that I could address as your First-Year Rep:</description></item><item><title>Johns' Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/john/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/john/</guid><description>Who Am I and What do I want? 🙃 Hey everyone! My name’s John. As a former High School Engineering Club executive, I’ve got experience hosting events and working with my peers. Whether you’re just starting out in Computer Science or you’ve been doing it for years, I’d have tons of plans for everyone to get involved as your first year rep. We’ll get through this year together!
1. Catch-Up and Study Sessions 📖 When we’re lagging behind or nearing exams, I’ll be hosting study sessions and mock exam sessions to help us pass those tough courses.</description></item><item><title>Nicholas' Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/nicholas/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/nicholas/</guid><description>Hello! My name is Nicholas O’Neil. I was born in Ottawa and I&amp;rsquo;ve spent most of my life in the area. I am a first-year Computer Science student. I am interested in the Game Development stream; however, I’m currently not in a stream as I would like to have some time to consider my options. Since discovering the CCSS, I have been enthusiastic about becoming involved, and I believe serving as the First Year Representative is the best way to do so!</description></item><item><title>Niraj's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/niraj/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/niraj/</guid><description>Hello there, my name is Niraj (or Kips!) and I am a first year student just like you!
I am an international student from India, I play the guitar, but you shouldn’t care too much about that. What you should care about is the fact that I have leadership experience from being captain of my school house and of the sports team for two years, and I am interested in running for first year representative of the CCSS.</description></item><item><title>Param's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/param/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/param/</guid><description>What will I do when I get elected as the CCSS First Year Representative? Background In the beginning stages of my programming career, I have experienced the difficulties that early programmers have gone through. Such as, finding the perfect tutorial, understanding online instructors or any programming classes. Using the knowledge of the struggles early programmers go through, I have decided to help first-year computer science students to succeed in university and also the future.</description></item><item><title>Ryan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/ryan/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2022-2023/ryan/</guid><description>Hey! I’m Ryan! As I am an active member of the Carleton Class of ‘26 and Carleton CS ‘26 (also the owner!) I’d like to put in more work to improve both the academic and the community side of the CCSS.
📢 Easy and Open Communication with CCSS 📢 As the owner of the two main first year servers with hundreds of CS students, I am fully immersed in the first year community.</description></item><item><title>Benjamin's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/academics/ben/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/academics/ben/</guid><description>Hey everyone! My name is Ben, and I’m currently in 1st year. Although I may not have much experience within the university, I believe that I can help contribute to your academic success. Computer science is a hard program to get through, but as Director of Academics, I want to make YOUR life easier.
Here are some ideas I have to meet that goal:
Course-specific study groups
There are a lot of courses that could benefit from organized group study.</description></item><item><title>Byron's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/social/byron/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/social/byron/</guid><description>Hi everyone! My name is Byron McDonald and I’m hoping to be the Director of Social on the upcoming year’s CCSS board of directors!
I have experience organizing events, hosting workshops, and leading volunteers, so I am prepared for the position. I also love meeting new people and making connections. Combining the two, I would love to bring fun and meaningful events to Carleton Computer Science students!
As the Director of Social, my main goals would be to organize connection building events and creating ways for students to relax and wind down.</description></item><item><title>Johns's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/social/john/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/social/john/</guid><description>Who Am I and What do I want? 🙃
Hey, everyone! My name’s John. I’m the CCSS First Year Representative and a current Board of Directors.
Over the course of the school year, I’ve hosted a games night, multiple study sessions, discord project development meetings, and had a hand in many other events. I’ve seen what works and what doesn&amp;rsquo;t. As the Director of Social, I’d have a few plans for the CCSS!</description></item><item><title>Kelly's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/community/kelly/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/community/kelly/</guid><description>Hey! I’m Kelly, a first year computer science student, and I’m running to be your next Director of Community. I’m passionate about making university a memorable experience for everyone and I believe that finding a sense of community is super important. As the Director of Community, I would love to:
1. Get you involved!
The CCSS is a place created by students, for students. Along with the super fun events, I would like to ensure lots of different volunteer opportunities for you to get involved so that you can make an impact.</description></item><item><title>Richard's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/vice-president/richard/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/vice-president/richard/</guid><description>Hi!
I am Richard Kim, a 4th year in Honours BCS, general stream. Some of you may know me from COMP 2406, as I have been a TA for 2406 4 times in a row. Or you may have seen me from SSSC (Science Student Success Centre). Where I have been mentoring CS students needing academic advice and running workshops and events, such as the Carleton Coding Challenge (I hope yall had fun in this!</description></item><item><title>Ryan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/finance/ryan/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/finance/ryan/</guid><description>Hello! I’m Ryan! Some of the goals that I have are:
Continuing and expanding the sale of merchandise
As a tradition, the CCSS has been selling hoodies and other merchandise. I plan on continuing this tradition and expanding into different types of merchandise which are priced fairly. As I am starting a business entrepreneurship minor next year, I will apply my new knowledge to these ventures to further performance and sales.</description></item><item><title>Shirley's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/academics/shirley/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/academics/shirley/</guid><description>Hello! My name is Shirley and I’ve had 2 years of experience on the CCSS council. I’ve conducted various events and hosted dozens of initiatives while being a representative. Once elected, I will organize a variety of initiatives to help with academic success, create opportunities, and introduce new topics within the tech industry! The details for the initiatives are below:
Study Sessions 📚
If elected, I will make sure to conduct study sessions on difficult courses to help prepare for midterms and exams.</description></item><item><title>Victor's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/president/victor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2023-2024/president/victor/</guid><description>As the Carleton Computer Science Society President, my platform will focus on three key areas: community building, education, and professional development.
🏡 Community Building:
Foster a welcoming and inclusive environment for all students, regardless of gender, ethnicity, or background. Promote collaboration between different Computer Science clubs and organizations to serve the student community better. Making myself available via Discord and our lounge to ask questions about either school, professional life and how they can get involved with our community 📚 Education:</description></item><item><title>Ari Rubin's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/ari/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/ari/</guid><description>Hi everybody, I’m Ari and I’m running for first year representative for the CCSS. As part of running my high school’s coding club I have experience teaching the ins and outs of object based programming and the skills for making cool projects. If I’m elected I hope to create more follow along workshops that would run people through making basic to advanced programs in an easy to understand way (I know I always get lost).</description></item><item><title>Sahil Gagvani 's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/sahil/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/sahil/</guid><description>Hey! My name is Sahil, and I’m running to be your First-Year rep at the CCSS! Having oranised and participated in various hackathons, seminars and workshops, I’ve concluded that the best way to grow as a professional in today’s tech scene is by developing soft skills; something that a classroom environment often fails to deliver. As a means to collectively work on our existing technical and interpersonal skills, I have planned various activities if I’m elected as your first year rep.</description></item><item><title>Rabten Tsering's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/rabten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/rabten/</guid><description>Hey fellow first years, my name is Rabten, Ragna on discord. As a first-year rep, I’m looking to connect with other first years and create a friendly environment in the discord and soon on campus. Schooling during a global pandemic leaves much to be desired, but I hope to make the best out of our situation and create an online and offline community that we can all thrive in! I would do this by (A) looking for more beginner-friendly events, as some people are learning comp sci for the first time (B) organize game nights for some quality social time and (C) create opportunities to interact with upper years because a little guidance is always useful!</description></item><item><title>Shirley Zhan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/shirley/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/shirley/</guid><description>Hello everyone, I’m Shirley.Z and I’m running for CCSS’s first-year rep! I’m going to make this really short since I know everyone’s really busy. I have a lot of experience working in leadership positions in various clubs and councils(can vouch as someone who’s joined 9+ extracurriculars overall in high school) so I think I’ll fit this position perfectly. On top of that, I also really love drawing and if I’m voted, I’ll be sure to bring some artistic and creative ideas to CCSS events.</description></item><item><title>Thushen Mohanarajah's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/thushen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/thushen/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s make this short and sweet. I&amp;rsquo;m Thushen! In my past experiences working at RBC as an Innovation Developer, attending hackathons and running the Computer Science Club at my high school. I learned pure coding skills aren&amp;rsquo;t enough. Networking is one of the most important skills to create opportunities, to learn and grow as an individual. This is what I have planned as your first year-representative:
Create an active discussion on how to network and explain how it helps you make friends, learn knowledge fast and helps you land an internship!</description></item><item><title>Adi's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/social/adi/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/social/adi/</guid><description>Hey fellow CCSS members! 👋🏾
I’m Aaditya Chopra (or you could just call me Adi) and I’m running to be your Director of Social for this year’s board of directors!
I’m someone who’s really passionate about getting involved with the student body, as well as event planning and having some fun, while also connecting with other people! As such, I would love to bring that passion to the board of directors this year as we transition from this weird online/in-person phase.</description></item><item><title>Amelie's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/academics/amelie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/academics/amelie/</guid><description>Hello world! My name is Amelie Haefele and I&amp;rsquo;m going into my third year here at Carleton while currently living on residence. I promise to encourage the academic opportunities and learning of all students in Carleton’s Computer Science Society and any others who wish to join. With the move to online many, including myself have found it much harder to learn.
To combat this I plan to create online and in person events so everyone can choose which medium they prefer.</description></item><item><title>Fahim's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/finance/fahim/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/finance/fahim/</guid><description>I would like to run for the Director of Finance because it&amp;rsquo;s a great opportunity for me to improve my current skills and give back to the computer science community. Ever since I came to Carleton I wanted to be as involved in the community as I could. Additionally, I&amp;rsquo;m well qualified for this position given my past jobs and academic courses. I’m currently doing a minor in business and have taken multiple business courses in high school.</description></item><item><title>Forest's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/vice-president/forest/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/vice-president/forest/</guid><description>Hi, I&amp;rsquo;m Forest!
I&amp;rsquo;m a 4th year student in the Game Development stream. I&amp;rsquo;m also Carleton&amp;rsquo;s Github Campus Expert; one of fewer than 10 in Canada. I&amp;rsquo;m a big advocate of open source development, primarily as a core developer of Veloren. Finally, I&amp;rsquo;m a contributor to the Rust language, where I focus on the community as a lead of the CTCFT team and the gamedev working group.
As the Vice President of the Carleton Computer Science Society, I would focus on empowering the other members of the board.</description></item><item><title>Matthew's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/president/matthew/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/president/matthew/</guid><description>Hey There, I&amp;rsquo;m Matthew! I’m a four-time elected CCSS executive and your current Director of Academics.
On behalf of the CCSS this year, I hosted over 20 events, organized some of our largest initiatives such as Carleton Dev Day, and delivered several projects to students such as DiscreteMath.ca. If elected, I will push the organization towards making an even greater impact on students while laying the foundations of success for the next generations of executives.</description></item><item><title>None</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/community/none/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/community/none/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Patrick's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/vice-president/patrick/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/vice-president/patrick/</guid><description>Hi everyone. My name is Patrick Ene and I’m running to be your next CCSS Vice President!
Firstly, a little about me. I am an international student from Nigeria and I’m also in the Game Dev stream. I generally enjoy spending my free time practicing with my guitar, listening to music, or playing video games (Apex anyone?).
I am considered outgoing and amiable. I am also a forward thinker and very goal-oriented.</description></item><item><title>Sarah's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/vice-president/sarah/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/vice-president/sarah/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Shirley's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/vice-president/shirley/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/vice-president/shirley/</guid><description>I think that CCSS is a wonderful organization that has brought a lot of wonderful joy to my life. It has supported many CS students through its various social and academic events. I myself have also had some experience organizing events and it was a very enjoyable experience.
As vice president, I will be sure to help organize the members and make sure the events flow well and are on schedule.</description></item><item><title>Victor's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/finance/victor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/general/2022-2023/finance/victor/</guid><description>Hey Everyone! My name is Victor Li, and this will be my second year running for the Director of Finance. I have a lot of experience doing personal and club finances from high school and CCSS. Some of my goals for this year are to:
Continue selling hoodies and other merchandise like t-shirts, pins, and laptop stickers using new designs and possibly use designs from the 2021-2022 Hoodie contest with artists' approval.</description></item></channel></rss>