<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Elections on Carleton Computer Science Society</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/</link><description>Recent content in Elections on Carleton Computer Science Society</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Ari Rubin's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/ari/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/ari/</guid><description>Hi everybody, I’m Ari and I’m running for first year representative for the CCSS. As part of running my high school’s coding club I have experience teaching the ins and outs of object based programming and the skills for making cool projects. If I’m elected I hope to create more follow along workshops that would run people through making basic to advanced programs in an easy to understand way (I know I always get lost).</description></item><item><title>Sahil Gagvani 's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/sahil/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/sahil/</guid><description>Hey! My name is Sahil, and I’m running to be your First-Year rep at the CCSS! Having oranised and participated in various hackathons, seminars and workshops, I’ve concluded that the best way to grow as a professional in today’s tech scene is by developing soft skills; something that a classroom environment often fails to deliver. As a means to collectively work on our existing technical and interpersonal skills, I have planned various activities if I’m elected as your first year rep.</description></item><item><title>Rabten Tsering's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/rabten/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/rabten/</guid><description>Hey fellow first years, my name is Rabten, Ragna on discord. As a first-year rep, I’m looking to connect with other first years and create a friendly environment in the discord and soon on campus. Schooling during a global pandemic leaves much to be desired, but I hope to make the best out of our situation and create an online and offline community that we can all thrive in! I would do this by (A) looking for more beginner-friendly events, as some people are learning comp sci for the first time (B) organize game nights for some quality social time and (C) create opportunities to interact with upper years because a little guidance is always useful!</description></item><item><title>Shirley Zhan's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/shirley/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/shirley/</guid><description>Hello everyone, I’m Shirley.Z and I’m running for CCSS’s first-year rep! I’m going to make this really short since I know everyone’s really busy. I have a lot of experience working in leadership positions in various clubs and councils(can vouch as someone who’s joined 9+ extracurriculars overall in high school) so I think I’ll fit this position perfectly. On top of that, I also really love drawing and if I’m voted, I’ll be sure to bring some artistic and creative ideas to CCSS events.</description></item><item><title>Thushen Mohanarajah's Platform</title><link>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/thushen/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Sep 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ccss.carleton.ca/elections/fyr/2021-2021/thushen/</guid><description>Let&amp;rsquo;s make this short and sweet. I&amp;rsquo;m Thushen! In my past experiences working at RBC as an Innovation Developer, attending hackathons and running the Computer Science Club at my high school. I learned pure coding skills aren&amp;rsquo;t enough. Networking is one of the most important skills to create opportunities, to learn and grow as an individual. This is what I have planned as your first year-representative:
Create an active discussion on how to network and explain how it helps you make friends, learn knowledge fast and helps you land an internship!</description></item></channel></rss>